<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>adversarial machine learning on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/adversarial-machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in adversarial machine learning on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/adversarial-machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SoK: Let the Privacy Games Begin! A Unified Treatment of Data Inference Privacy in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-let-the-privacy-games-begin-a-unified-treatment-of-data-inference-privacy-in-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-let-the-privacy-games-begin-a-unified-treatment-of-data-inference-privacy-in-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on the use of cryptographic-style games to model inference privacy is published in IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland):
 Ahmed Salem, Giovanni Cherubin, , Boris Köpf, Andrew Paverd, Anshuman Suri, Shruti Tople, and Santiago Zanella-Béguelin. SoK: Let the Privacy Games Begin! A Unified Treatment of Data Inference Privacy in Machine Learning. IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, 2023. [Arxiv]    Tired of diverse definitions of machine learning privacy risks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVPR 2023: Manipulating Transfer Learning for Property Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cvpr-2023-manipulating-transfer-learning-for-property-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cvpr-2023-manipulating-transfer-learning-for-property-inference/</guid>
      <description>Manipulating Transfer Learning for Property Inference Transfer learning is a popular method to train deep learning models efficiently. By reusing parameters from upstream pre-trained models, the downstream trainer can use fewer computing resources to train downstream models, compared to training models from scratch.
The figure below shows the typical process of transfer learning for vision tasks:
   However, the nature of transfer learning can be exploited by a malicious upstream trainer, leading to severe risks to the downstream trainer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICO Challenge in Membership Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/mico-challenge-in-membership-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/mico-challenge-in-membership-inference/</guid>
      <description>Anshuman Suri wrote up an interesting post on his experience with the MICO Challenge, a membership inference competition that was part of SaTML. Anshuman placed second in the competition (on the CIFAR data set), where the metric is highest true positive rate at a 0.1 false positive rate over a set of models (some trained using differential privacy and some without).
Anshuman&amp;rsquo;s post describes the methods he used and his experience in the competition: My submission to the MICO Challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voice of America interview on ChatGPT</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/voice-of-america-interview-on-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/voice-of-america-interview-on-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed for a Voice of America story (in Russian) on the impact of chatGPT and similar tools.
   Full story: https://youtu.be/dFuunAFX9y4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uh-oh, there&#39;s a new way to poison code models</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/uh-oh-theres-a-new-way-to-poison-code-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/uh-oh-theres-a-new-way-to-poison-code-models/</guid>
      <description>Jack Clark&amp;rsquo;s Import AI, 16 Jan 2023 includes a nice description of our work on TrojanPuzzle:
####################################################
Uh-oh, there&#39;s a new way to poison code models - and it&#39;s really hard to detect:
…TROJANPUZZLE is a clever way to trick your code model into betraying you - if you can poison the undelrying dataset…
Researchers with the University of California, Santa Barbara, Microsoft Corporation, and the University of Virginia have come up with some clever, subtle ways to poison the datasets used to train code models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trojan Puzzle attack trains AI assistants into suggesting malicious code</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/trojan-puzzle-attack-trains-ai-assistants-into-suggesting-malicious-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/trojan-puzzle-attack-trains-ai-assistants-into-suggesting-malicious-code/</guid>
      <description>Bleeping Computer has a story on our work (in collaboration with Microsoft Research) on poisoning code suggestion models:
Trojan Puzzle attack trains AI assistants into suggesting malicious code By Bill Toulas
    Researchers at the universities of California, Virginia, and Microsoft have devised a new poisoning attack that could trick AI-based coding assistants into suggesting dangerous code.
Named &amp;lsquo;Trojan Puzzle,&amp;rsquo; the attack stands out for bypassing static detection and signature-based dataset cleansing models, resulting in the AI models being trained to learn how to reproduce dangerous payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Submission Award at VISxAI 2022</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/best-submission-award-at-visxai-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/best-submission-award-at-visxai-2022/</guid>
      <description>Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility by Evan Rose, Fnu Suya, and David Evans won the Best Submission Award at the 5th Workshop on Visualization for AI Explainability.
Undergraduate student Evan Rose led the work and presented it at VISxAI in Oklahoma City, 17 October 2022.
 Congratulations to #VISxAI&amp;#39;s Best Submission Awards:
🏆 K-Means Clustering: An Explorable Explainer by @yizhe_ang https://t.co/BULW33WPzo
🏆 Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility by Evan Rose, @suyafnu, and @UdacityDave https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Poisoning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/visualizing-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/visualizing-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>How does a poisoning attack work and why are some groups more susceptible to being victimized by a poisoning attack?
We&amp;rsquo;ve posted work that helps understand how poisoning attacks work with some engaging visualizations:
Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility
An Experimental Exploration on the Effectiveness of Poisoning Attacks
Evan Rose, Fnu Suya, and David Evans
 
Follow the link to try the interactive version!   Machine learning is susceptible to poisoning attacks in which adversaries inject maliciously crafted training data into the training set to induce specific model behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Zhang!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-zhang/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Xiao Zhang for successfully defending his PhD thesis!
 Dr. Zhang and his PhD committee: Somesh Jha (University of Wisconsin), David Evans, Tom Fletcher; Tianxi&amp;nbsp;Li&amp;nbsp;(UVA&amp;nbsp;Statistics), David&amp;nbsp;Wu&amp;nbsp;(UT&amp;nbsp;Austin), Mohammad&amp;nbsp;Mahmoody; Xiao&amp;nbsp;Zhang.   Xiao will join the CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security in Saarbrücken, Germany this fall as a tenure-track faculty member.
  From Characterizing Intrinsic Robustness to Adversarially Robust Machine Learning   The prevalence of adversarial examples raises questions about the reliability of machine learning systems, especially for their deployment in critical applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICLR 2022: Understanding Intrinsic Robustness Using Label Uncertainty</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2022-understanding-intrinsic-robustness-using-label-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2022-understanding-intrinsic-robustness-using-label-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>(Blog post written by Xiao Zhang)
Motivated by the empirical hardness of developing robust classifiers against adversarial perturbations, researchers began asking the question “Does there even exist a robust classifier?”. This is formulated as the intrinsic robustness problem (Mahloujifar et al., 2019), where the goal is to characterize the maximum adversarial robustness possible for a given robust classification problem. Building upon the connection between adversarial robustness and classifier’s error region, it has been shown that if we restrict the search to the set of imperfect classifiers, the intrinsic robustness problem can be reduced to the concentration of measure problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Research Summit: Surprising (and unsurprising) Inference Risks in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-research-summit-surprising-and-unsurprising-inference-risks-in-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-research-summit-surprising-and-unsurprising-inference-risks-in-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the Practical and Theoretical Privacy of Machine Learning Training Pipelines Workshop at the Microsoft Research Summit (21 October 2021):
 Surprising (and Unsurprising) Inference Risks in Machine Learning [PDF]    The work by Bargav Jayaraman (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) that I talked about on improving membership inference attacks is described in more details here:
  Bargav Jayaraman, Lingxiao Wang, Katherine Knipmeyer, Quanquan Gu, David Evans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UVA News Article</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/uva-news-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/uva-news-article/</guid>
      <description>UVA News has an article by Audra Book on our research on security and privacy of machine learning (with some very nice quotes from several students in the group, and me saying something positive about the NSA!): Computer science professor David Evans and his team conduct experiments to understand security and privacy risks associated with machine learning, 8 September 2021.
David Evans, professor of computer science in the University of Virginia School of Engineering and Applied Science, is leading research to understand how machine learning models can be compromised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-Targeted Poisoning Attacks with Provable Convergence</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/model-targeted-poisoning-attacks-with-provable-convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/model-targeted-poisoning-attacks-with-provable-convergence/</guid>
      <description>(Post by Sean Miller, using images adapted from Suya&amp;rsquo;s talk slides)
Data Poisoning Attacks Machine learning models are often trained using data from untrusted sources, leaving them open to poisoning attacks where adversaries use their control over a small fraction of that training data to poison the model in a particular way.
Most work on poisoning attacks is directly driven by an attacker&amp;rsquo;s objective, where the adversary chooses poisoning points that maximize some target objective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICLR DPML 2021: Inference Risks for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-dpml-2021-inference-risks-for-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-dpml-2021-inference-risks-for-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I gave an invited talk at the Distributed and Private Machine Learning (DPML) workshop at ICLR 2021 on Inference Risks for Machine Learning.
  The talk mostly covers work by Bargav Jayaraman on evaluating privacy in machine learning and connecting attribute inference and imputation, and recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Hide a Backdoor</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/how-to-hide-a-backdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/how-to-hide-a-backdoor/</guid>
      <description>The Register has an article on our recent work on Stealthy Backdoors as Compression Artifacts: Thomas Claburn, How to hide a backdoor in AI software — Neural networks can be aimed to misbehave when squeezed, The Register, 5 May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codaspy 2021 Keynote: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the 11th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy:
 When Models Learn Too Much [PDF]   The talk includes Bargav Jayaraman&amp;rsquo;s work (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) on evaluating privacy in machine learning, as well as more recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference attacks, and Bargav on attribute inference and imputation:
 Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice   “When models learn too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrySP Talk: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/crysp-talk-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/crysp-talk-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk on When Models Learn Too Much at the University of Waterloo (virtually) in the CrySP Speaker Series on Privacy (29 March 2021):
    Abstract  Statistical machine learning uses training data to produce models that capture patterns in that data. When models are trained on private data, such as medical records or personal emails, there is a risk that those models not only learn the hoped-for patterns, but will also learn and expose sensitive information about their training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Estimation of Concentration (ICLR 2021)</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/improved-estimation-of-concentration-iclr-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/improved-estimation-of-concentration-iclr-2021/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on Improved Estimation of Concentration Under ℓp-Norm Distance Metrics Using Half Spaces (Jack Prescott, Xiao Zhang, and David Evans) will be presented at ICLR 2021.
Abstract: Concentration of measure has been argued to be the fundamental cause of adversarial vulnerability. Mahloujifar et al. (2019) presented an empirical way to measure the concentration of a data distribution using samples, and employed it to find lower bounds on intrinsic robustness for several benchmark datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Security Data Science Colloquium: Inference Privacy in Theory and Practice</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-security-data-science-colloquium-inference-privacy-in-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-security-data-science-colloquium-inference-privacy-in-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the Microsoft Security Data Science Colloquium:
When Models Learn Too Much: Inference Privacy in Theory and Practice [PDF]
   The talk is mostly about Bargav Jayaraman&amp;rsquo;s work (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) on evaluating privacy:
 Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversarially Robust Representations</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/robustrepresentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/robustrepresentations/</guid>
      <description>Post by Sicheng Zhu
With the rapid development of deep learning and the explosive growth of unlabeled data, representation learning is becoming increasingly important. It has made impressive applications such as pre-trained language models (e.g., BERT and GPT-3).
Popular as it is, representation learning raises concerns about the robustness of learned representations under adversarial settings. For example, how can we compare the robustness to different representations, and how can we build representations that enable robust downstream classifiers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Robustness using Conditional GANs</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/intrinsic-robustness-using-conditional-gans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/intrinsic-robustness-using-conditional-gans/</guid>
      <description>The video of Xiao&amp;rsquo;s presentation for AISTATS 2020 is now available: Understanding the Intrinsic Robustness of Image Distributions using Conditional Generative Models
Starting with Gilmer et al. (2018), several works have demonstrated the inevitability of adversarial examples based on different assumptions about the underlying input probability space. It remains unclear, however, whether these results apply to natural image distributions. In this work, we assume the underlying data distribution is captured by some conditional generative model, and prove intrinsic robustness bounds for a general class of classifiers, which solves an open problem in Fawzi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Batch Attacks at USENIX Security 2020</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/hybrid-batch-attacks-at-usenix-security-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/hybrid-batch-attacks-at-usenix-security-2020/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the video for Suya&amp;rsquo;s presentation on Hybrid Batch Attacks at USENIX Security 2020:
 
Download Video [mp4]
 Blog Post
Paper: [PDF] [arXiv]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips2019/</guid>
      <description> Here&#39;s a video of Xiao Zhang&#39;s presentation at NeurIPS 2019: https://slideslive.com/38921718/track-2-session-1 (starting at 26:50)  See this post for info on the paper. Here are a few pictures from NeurIPS 2019 (by Sicheng Zhu and Mohammad Mahmoody):   




 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USENIX Security 2020: Hybrid Batch Attacks</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2020-hybrid-batch-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2020-hybrid-batch-attacks/</guid>
      <description>New: Video Presentation
Finding Black-box Adversarial Examples with Limited Queries Black-box attacks generate adversarial examples (AEs) against deep neural networks with only API access to the victim model.
Existing black-box attacks can be grouped into two main categories:
  Transfer Attacks use white-box attacks on local models to find candidate adversarial examples that transfer to the target model.
  Optimization Attacks use queries to the target model and apply optimization techniques to search for adversarial examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2019: Empirically Measuring Concentration</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2019-empirically-measuring-concentration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2019-empirically-measuring-concentration/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang will present our work (with Saeed Mahloujifar and Mohamood Mahmoody) as a spotlight at NeurIPS 2019, Vancouver, 10 December 2019.
Recent theoretical results, starting with Gilmer et al.&amp;rsquo;s Adversarial Spheres (2018), show that if inputs are drawn from a concentrated metric probability space, then adversarial examples with small perturbation are inevitable.c The key insight from this line of research is that concentration of measure gives lower bound on adversarial risk for a large collection of classifiers (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Symposium Posters</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/research-symposium-posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/research-symposium-posters/</guid>
      <description>Five students from our group presented posters at the department&amp;rsquo;s Fall Research Symposium:
 
Anshuman Suri&#39;s Overview Talk   Bargav Jayaraman, Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning In Practice [Poster]
[Paper (USENIX Security 2019)]  

 Hannah Chen [Poster]  

 Xiao Zhang [Poster]
[Paper (NeurIPS 2019)]  

 Mainudding Jonas [Poster]  

 Fnu Suya [Poster]
[Paper (USENIX Security 2020)]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSAD Trustworthy Machine Learning Mini-Course</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/fosad2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/fosad2019/</guid>
      <description>I taught a mini-course on Trustworthy Machine Learning at the 19th International School on Foundations of Security Analysis and Design in Bertinoro, Italy.
 Slides from my three (two-hour) lectures are posted below, along with some links to relevant papers and resources.
Class 1: Introduction/Attacks    The PDF malware evasion attack is described in this paper:
 Weilin Xu, Yanjun Qi, and David Evans. Automatically Evading Classifiers: A Case Study on PDF Malware Classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Security and Privacy Workshop</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/google-security-and-privacy-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/google-security-and-privacy-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I presented a short talk at a workshop at Google on Adversarial ML: Closing Gaps between Theory and Practice (mostly fun for the movie of me trying to solve Google&amp;rsquo;s CAPTCHA on the last slide):
 Getting the actual screencast to fit into the limited time for this talk challenged the limits of my video editing skills.
 I can say with some confidence, Google does donuts much better than they do cookies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brink Essay: AI Systems Are Complex and Fragile. Here Are Four Key Risks to Understand.</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/brink-essay-ai-systems-are-complex-and-fragile.-here-are-four-key-risks-to-understand./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/brink-essay-ai-systems-are-complex-and-fragile.-here-are-four-key-risks-to-understand./</guid>
      <description>Brink News (a publication of The Atlantic) published my essay on the risks of deploying AI systems.
   Artificial intelligence technologies have the potential to transform society in positive and powerful ways. Recent studies have shown computing systems that can outperform humans at numerous once-challenging tasks, ranging from performing medical diagnoses and reviewing legal contracts to playing Go and recognizing human emotions. 
Despite these successes, AI systems are fundamentally fragile — and the ways they can fail are poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost-Sensitive Adversarial Robustness at ICLR 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cost-sensitive-adversarial-robustness-at-iclr-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cost-sensitive-adversarial-robustness-at-iclr-2019/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang will present Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples on May 7 (4:30-6:30pm) at ICLR 2019 in New Orleans.
   Paper: [PDF] [OpenReview] [ArXiv]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirically Measuring Concentration</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/empirically-measuring-concentration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/empirically-measuring-concentration/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang and Saeed Mahloujifar will present our work on Empirically Measuring Concentration: Fundamental Limits on Intrinsic Robustness at two workshops May 6 at ICLR 2019 in New Orleans: Debugging Machine Learning Models and Safe Machine Learning: Specification, Robustness and Assurance.
Paper: [PDF]
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JASON Spring Meeting: Adversarial Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/jason-spring-meeting-adversarial-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/jason-spring-meeting-adversarial-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege of speaking at the JASON Spring Meeting, undoubtably one of the most diverse meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve been part of with talks on hypersonic signatures (from my DSSG 2008-2009 colleague, Ian Boyd), FBI DNA, nuclear proliferation in Iran, engineering biological materials, and the 2020 census (including a very interesting presentatino from John Abowd on the differential privacy mechanisms they have developed and evaluated). (Unfortunately, my lack of security clearance kept me out of the SCIF used for the talks on quantum computing and more sensitive topics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Dr. Xu!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-xu/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Weilin Xu for successfully defending his PhD Thesis!
   Weilin&#39;s Committee: Homa Alemzadeh, Yanjun Qi, Patrick McDaniel (on screen), David Evans, Vicente Ordóñez Román    Improving Robustness of Machine Learning Models using Domain Knowledge  Although machine learning techniques have achieved great success in many areas, such as computer vision, natural language processing, and computer security, recent studies have shown that they are not robust under attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Fools</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/deep-fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/deep-fools/</guid>
      <description>New Electronics has an article that includes my Deep Learning and Security Workshop talk: Deep fools, 21 January 2019.
A better version of the image Mainuddin Jonas produced that they use (which they screenshot from the talk video) is below:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICLR 2019: Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2019-cost-sensitive-robustness-against-adversarial-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2019-cost-sensitive-robustness-against-adversarial-examples/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang and my paper on Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples has been accepted to ICLR 2019.
Several recent works have developed methods for training classifiers that are certifiably robust against norm-bounded adversarial perturbations. However, these methods assume that all the adversarial transformations provide equal value for adversaries, which is seldom the case in real-world applications. We advocate for cost-sensitive robustness as the criteria for measuring the classifier&amp;rsquo;s performance for specific tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Machine Learning Ever Be Trustworthy?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/can-machine-learning-ever-be-trustworthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/can-machine-learning-ever-be-trustworthy/</guid>
      <description>I gave the Booz Allen Hamilton Distinguished Colloquium at the University of Maryland on Can Machine Learning Ever Be Trustworthy?.
 [Video](https://vid.umd.edu/detsmediasite/Play/e8009558850944bfb2cac477f8d741711d?catalog=74740199-303c-49a2-9025-2dee0a195650) &amp;middot; [SpeakerDeck](https://speakerdeck.com/evansuva/can-machine-learning-ever-be-trustworthy) 
 Abstract Machine learning has produced extraordinary results over the past few years, and machine learning systems are rapidly being deployed for critical tasks, even in adversarial environments. This talk will survey some of the reasons building trustworthy machine learning systems is inherently impossible, and dive into some recent research on adversarial examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Center for Trustworthy Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/center-for-trustworthy-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/center-for-trustworthy-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>The National Science Foundation announced the Center for Trustworthy Machine Learning today, a new five-year SaTC Frontier Center &amp;ldquo;to develop a rigorous understanding of the security risks of the use of machine learning and to devise the tools, metrics and methods to manage and mitigate security vulnerabilities.&amp;rdquo;
The Center is lead by Patrick McDaniel at Penn State University, and in addition to our group, includes Dan Boneh and Percy Liang (Stanford University), Kamalika Chaudhuri (University of California San Diego), Somesh Jha (University of Wisconsin) and Dawn Song (University of California Berkeley).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence: the new ghost in the machine</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/artificial-intelligence-the-new-ghost-in-the-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/artificial-intelligence-the-new-ghost-in-the-machine/</guid>
      <description>Engineering and Technology Magazine (a publication of the British [Institution of Engineering and Technology]() has an article that highlights adversarial machine learning research: Artificial intelligence: the new ghost in the machine, 10 October 2018, by Chris Edwards.
  Although researchers such as David Evans of the University of Virginia see a full explanation being a little way off in the future, the massive number of parameters encoded by DNNs and the avoidance of overtraining due to SGD may have an answer to why the networks can hallucinate images and, as a result, see things that are not there and ignore those that are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USENIX Security 2018</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2018/</guid>
      <description>Three SRG posters were presented at USENIX Security Symposium 2018 in Baltimore, Maryland:
 Nathaniel Grevatt (GDPR-Compliant Data Processing: Improving Pseudonymization with Multi-Party Computation) Matthew Wallace and Parvesh Samayamanthula (Deceiving Privacy Policy Classifiers with Adversarial Examples) Guy Verrier (How is GDPR Affecting Privacy Policies?, joint with Haonan Chen and Yuan Tian)  
         There were also a surprising number of appearances by an unidentified unicorn:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutually Assured Destruction and the Impending AI Apocalypse</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/mutually-assured-destruction-and-the-impending-ai-apocalypse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/mutually-assured-destruction-and-the-impending-ai-apocalypse/</guid>
      <description>I gave a keynote talk at USENIX Workshop of Offensive Technologies, Baltimore, Maryland, 13 August 2018. The title and abstract are what I provided for the WOOT program, but unfortunately (or maybe fortunately for humanity!) I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to actually figure out a talk to match the title and abstract I provided.
 The history of security includes a long series of arms races, where a new technology emerges and is subsequently developed and exploited by both defenders and attackers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependable and Secure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/dependable-and-secure-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/dependable-and-secure-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I co-organized, with Homa Alemzadeh and Karthik Pattabiraman, a workshop on trustworthy machine learning attached to DSN 2018, in Luxembourg: DSML: Dependable and Secure Machine Learning.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DLS Keynote: Is &#39;adversarial examples&#39; an Adversarial Example?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/dls-keynote-is-adversarial-examples-an-adversarial-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/dls-keynote-is-adversarial-examples-an-adversarial-example/</guid>
      <description>I gave a keynote talk at the 1st Deep Learning and Security Workshop (co-located with the 39th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy). San Francisco, California. 24 May 2018

  
  
Abstract

 Over the past few years, there has been an explosion of research in security of machine learning and on adversarial examples in particular. Although this is in many ways a new and immature research area, the general problem of adversarial examples has been a core problem in information security for thousands of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Last 3000 Years of Adversarial Examples</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/lessons-from-the-last-3000-years-of-adversarial-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/lessons-from-the-last-3000-years-of-adversarial-examples/</guid>
      <description>I spoke on Lessons from the Last 3000 Years of Adversarial Examples at Huawei’s Strategy and Technology Workshop in Shenzhen, China, 15 May 2018.    We also got to tour Huawei&amp;#8217;s new research and development campus, under construction about 40 minutes from Shenzhen. It is pretty close to Disneyland, with its own railroad and villages themed after different European cities (Paris, Bologna, etc.).


Huawei&amp;#8217;s New Research and Development Campus [More Pictures]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Squeezing at NDSS</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/feature-squeezing-at-ndss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/feature-squeezing-at-ndss/</guid>
      <description>Weilin Xu presented Feature Squeezing: Detecting Adversarial Examples in Deep Neural Networks at the Network and Distributed System Security Symposium 2018. San Diego, CA. 21 February 2018.



 Paper: Weilin Xu, David Evans, Yanjun Qi. Feature Squeezing: Detecting Adversarial Examples in Deep Neural Networks. NDSS 2018. [PDF]
Project Site: EvadeML.org</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
