<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bias on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/bias/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bias on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/bias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Mismeasure of Man and Models</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/the-mismeasure-of-man-and-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/the-mismeasure-of-man-and-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;evaluating-allocational-harms-in-large-language-models&#34;&gt;Evaluating Allocational Harms in Large Language Models&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog post written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://hannahxchen.github.io/&#34;&gt;Hannah Chen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our work considers &lt;i&gt;allocational harms&lt;/i&gt; that arise when model predictions are used to distribute scarce resources or opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-bias-metrics-do-not-reliably-reflect-allocation-disparities&#34;&gt;Current Bias Metrics Do Not Reliably Reflect Allocation Disparities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several methods have been proposed to audit large language models (LLMs) for bias when used in critical decision-making, such as resume screening for hiring. Yet, these methods focus on &lt;i&gt;predictions&lt;/i&gt;, without considering how the predictions are used to make &lt;i&gt;decisions&lt;/i&gt;. In many settings, making decisions involve prioritizing options due to limited resource constraints. We find that prediction-based evaluation methods, which measure bias as the &lt;i&gt;average performance gap&lt;/i&gt; (δ) in prediction outcomes, do not reliably reflect disparities in allocation decision outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjectives Can Reveal Gender Biases Within NLP Models</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/adjectives-can-reveal-gender-biases-within-nlp-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/adjectives-can-reveal-gender-biases-within-nlp-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Post by &lt;strong&gt;Jason Briegel&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hannahxchen.github.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hannah Chen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because NLP models are trained with human corpora (and now,&#xA;increasingly on text generated by other NLP models that were&#xA;originally trained on human language), they are prone to inheriting&#xA;common human stereotypes and biases. This is problematic, because with&#xA;their growing prominence they may further propagate these stereotypes&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1906.08976&#34;&gt;(Sun et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;. For example,&#xA;interest is growing in mitigating bias in the field of machine&#xA;translation, where systems such as Google translate were observed to&#xA;default to translating gender-neutral pronouns as male pronouns, even&#xA;with feminine cues &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1162/tacl_a_00401&#34;&gt;(Savoldi et al.,&#xA;2021)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
