<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Trail of Crumbs</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/googles-trail-of-crumbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/googles-trail-of-crumbs/</guid>
      <description>Matt Stoller published my essay on Google&amp;rsquo;s decision to abandon its Privacy Sandbox Initiative in his Big newsletter:&#xA;Google&#39;s Trail of Crumbs by Matt Stoller&#xA;Google is too big to get rid of cookies. Even when it wants to protect users, it can&#39;t.&#xA;Read on Substack For more technical background on this, see Minjun&amp;rsquo;s paper: Evaluating Google&amp;rsquo;s Protected Audience Protocol in PETS 2024.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology: US authorities survey AI ecosystem through antitrust lens</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/technology-us-authorities-survey-ai-ecosystem-through-antitrust-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/technology-us-authorities-survey-ai-ecosystem-through-antitrust-lens/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m quoted in this article for the International Bar Association:&#xA;Technology: US authorities survey AI ecosystem through antitrust lens&#xA;William Roberts, IBA US Correspondent&#xA;Friday 2 August 2024&#xA;Antitrust authorities in the US are targeting the new frontier of artificial intelligence (AI) for potential enforcement action. &amp;hellip;&#xA;Jonathan Kanter, Assistant Attorney General for the Antitrust Division of the DoJ, warns that the government sees ‘structures and trends in AI that should give us pause’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Guttag Birthday Celebration</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/john-guttag-birthday-celebration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/john-guttag-birthday-celebration/</guid>
      <description>Maggie Makar organized a celebration for the 75th birthday of my PhD advisor, John Guttag.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to attend in person, unfortunately, but the occasion provided an opportunity to create a poster that looks back on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done since I started working with John over 30 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Suri!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-suri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-suri/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Anshuman Suri for successfully defending his PhD thesis!&#xA;Tianhao Wang, Dr. Anshuman Suri, Nando Fioretto, Cong Shen&#xA;On Screen: David Evans, Giuseppe Ateniese Inference Privacy in Machine Learning Using machine learning models comes at the risk of leaking information about data used in their training and deployment. This leakage can expose sensitive information about properties of the underlying data distribution, data from participating users, or even individual records in the training data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduation 2024</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/graduation-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/graduation-2024/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SaTML Talk: SoK: Pitfalls in Evaluating Black-Box Attacks</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/satml-talk-sok-pitfalls-in-evaluating-black-box-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/satml-talk-sok-pitfalls-in-evaluating-black-box-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Anshuman Suri&amp;rsquo;s talk at IEEE Conference on Secure and Trustworthy Machine Learning (SaTML) is now available:&#xA;See the earlier blog post for more on the work, and the paper at https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.17534.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Lamp!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-lamp/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Wang (Committee Chair), Miaomiao Zhang, Lu Feng (Co-Advisor), Dr. Josie Lamp, David Evans&#xA;On screen: Sula Mazimba, Rich Nguyen, Tingting Zhu Congratulations to Josephine Lamp for successfully defending her PhD thesis!&#xA;Trustworthy Clinical Decision Support Systems for Medical Trajectories The explosion of medical sensors and wearable devices has resulted in the collection of large amounts of medical trajectories. Medical trajectories are time series that provide a nuanced look into patient conditions and their changes over time, allowing for a more fine-grained understanding of patient health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Membership Inference Attacks Work on Large Language Models?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/do-membership-inference-attacks-work-on-large-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/do-membership-inference-attacks-work-on-large-language-models/</guid>
      <description>MIMIR logo. Image credit: GPT-4 + DALL-E Paper Code Data Membership inference attacks (MIAs) attempt to predict whether a particular datapoint is a member of a target model&amp;rsquo;s training data. Despite extensive research on traditional machine learning models, there has been limited work studying MIA on the pre-training data of large language models (LLMs).&#xA;We perform a large-scale evaluation of MIAs over a suite of language models (LMs) trained on the Pile, ranging from 160M to 12B parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoK: Pitfalls in Evaluating Black-Box Attacks</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-pitfalls-in-evaluating-black-box-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-pitfalls-in-evaluating-black-box-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Post by Anshuman Suri and Fnu Suya&#xA;Much research has studied black-box attacks on image classifiers, where adversaries generate adversarial examples against unknown target models without having access to their internal information. Our analysis of over 164 attacks (published in 102 major security, machine learning and security conferences) shows how these works make different assumptions about the adversary’s knowledge.&#xA;The current literature lacks cohesive organization centered around the threat model. Our SoK paper (to appear at IEEE SaTML 2024) introduces a taxonomy for systematizing these attacks and demonstrates the importance of careful evaluations that consider adversary resources and threat models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2023: What Distributions are Robust to Poisoning Attacks?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2023-what-distributions-are-robust-to-poisoning-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2023-what-distributions-are-robust-to-poisoning-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Post by Fnu Suya&#xA;Data poisoning attacks are recognized as a top concern in the industry [1]. We focus on conventional indiscriminate data poisoning attacks, where an adversary injects a few crafted examples into the training data with the goal of increasing the test error of the induced model. Despite recent advances, indiscriminate poisoning attacks on large neural networks remain challenging [2]. In this work (to be presented at NeurIPS 2023), we revisit the vulnerabilities of more extensively studied linear models under indiscriminate poisoning attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjectives Can Reveal Gender Biases Within NLP Models</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/adjectives-can-reveal-gender-biases-within-nlp-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/adjectives-can-reveal-gender-biases-within-nlp-models/</guid>
      <description>Post by Jason Briegel and Hannah Chen&#xA;Because NLP models are trained with human corpora (and now, increasingly on text generated by other NLP models that were originally trained on human language), they are prone to inheriting common human stereotypes and biases. This is problematic, because with their growing prominence they may further propagate these stereotypes (Sun et al., 2019). For example, interest is growing in mitigating bias in the field of machine translation, where systems such as Google translate were observed to default to translating gender-neutral pronouns as male pronouns, even with feminine cues (Savoldi et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Suya!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-suya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-suya/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Fnu Suya for successfully defending his PhD thesis!&#xA;Suya will join the Unversity of Maryland as a MC2 Postdoctoral Fellow at the Maryland Cybersecurity Center this fall.&#xA;On the Limits of Data Poisoning Attacks Current machine learning models require large amounts of labeled training data, which are often collected from untrusted sources. Models trained on these potentially manipulated data points are prone to data poisoning attacks. My research aims to gain a deeper understanding on the limits of two types of data poisoning attacks: indiscriminate poisoning attacks, where the attacker aims to increase the test error on the entire dataset; and subpopulation poisoning attacks, where the attacker aims to increase the test error on a defined subset of the distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoK: Let the Privacy Games Begin! A Unified Treatment of Data Inference Privacy in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-let-the-privacy-games-begin-a-unified-treatment-of-data-inference-privacy-in-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-let-the-privacy-games-begin-a-unified-treatment-of-data-inference-privacy-in-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on the use of cryptographic-style games to model inference privacy is published in IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVPR 2023: Manipulating Transfer Learning for Property Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cvpr-2023-manipulating-transfer-learning-for-property-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cvpr-2023-manipulating-transfer-learning-for-property-inference/</guid>
      <description>Manipulating Transfer Learning for Property Inference Transfer learning is a popular method to train deep learning models efficiently. By reusing parameters from upstream pre-trained models, the downstream trainer can use fewer computing resources to train downstream models, compared to training models from scratch.&#xA;The figure below shows the typical process of transfer learning for vision tasks:&#xA;However, the nature of transfer learning can be exploited by a malicious upstream trainer, leading to severe risks to the downstream trainer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MICO Challenge in Membership Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/mico-challenge-in-membership-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/mico-challenge-in-membership-inference/</guid>
      <description>Anshuman Suri wrote up an interesting post on his experience with the MICO Challenge, a membership inference competition that was part of SaTML. Anshuman placed second in the competition (on the CIFAR data set), where the metric is highest true positive rate at a 0.1 false positive rate over a set of models (some trained using differential privacy and some without).&#xA;Anshuman&amp;rsquo;s post describes the methods he used and his experience in the competition: My submission to the MICO Challenge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voice of America interview on ChatGPT</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/voice-of-america-interview-on-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/voice-of-america-interview-on-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed for a Voice of America story (in Russian) on the impact of chatGPT and similar tools.&#xA;Full story: https://youtu.be/dFuunAFX9y4</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uh-oh, there&#39;s a new way to poison code models</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/uh-oh-theres-a-new-way-to-poison-code-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/uh-oh-theres-a-new-way-to-poison-code-models/</guid>
      <description>Jack Clark&amp;rsquo;s Import AI, 16 Jan 2023 includes a nice description of our work on TrojanPuzzle:&#xA;####################################################&#xA;Uh-oh, there&#39;s a new way to poison code models - and it&#39;s really hard to detect:&#xA;…TROJANPUZZLE is a clever way to trick your code model into betraying you - if you can poison the undelrying dataset…&#xA;Researchers with the University of California, Santa Barbara, Microsoft Corporation, and the University of Virginia have come up with some clever, subtle ways to poison the datasets used to train code models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trojan Puzzle attack trains AI assistants into suggesting malicious code</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/trojan-puzzle-attack-trains-ai-assistants-into-suggesting-malicious-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/trojan-puzzle-attack-trains-ai-assistants-into-suggesting-malicious-code/</guid>
      <description>Bleeping Computer has a story on our work (in collaboration with Microsoft Research) on poisoning code suggestion models:&#xA;Trojan Puzzle attack trains AI assistants into suggesting malicious code By Bill Toulas&#xA;Researchers at the universities of California, Virginia, and Microsoft have devised a new poisoning attack that could trick AI-based coding assistants into suggesting dangerous code.&#xA;Named &amp;lsquo;Trojan Puzzle,&amp;rsquo; the attack stands out for bypassing static detection and signature-based dataset cleansing models, resulting in the AI models being trained to learn how to reproduce dangerous payloads.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting Distribution Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/dissecting-distribution-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/dissecting-distribution-inference/</guid>
      <description>(Cross-post by Anshuman Suri)&#xA;Distribution inference attacks aims to infer statistical properties of data used to train machine learning models. These attacks are sometimes surprisingly potent, as we demonstrated in previous work.&#xA;KL Divergence Attack Most attacks against distribution inference involve training a meta-classifier, either using model parameters in white-box settings (Ganju et al., Property Inference Attacks on Fully Connected Neural Networks using Permutation Invariant Representations, CCS 2018), or using model predictions in black-box scenarios (Zhang et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cray Distinguished Speaker: On Leaky Models and Unintended Inferences</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cray-distinguished-speaker-on-leaky-models-and-unintended-inferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cray-distinguished-speaker-on-leaky-models-and-unintended-inferences/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the slides from my Cray Distinguished Speaker talk on On Leaky Models and Unintended Inferences: [PDF]&#xA;The chatGPT limerick version of my talk abstract is much better than mine:&#xA;A machine learning model, oh so grand&#xA;With data sets that it held in its hand&#xA;It performed quite well&#xA;But secrets to tell&#xA;And an adversary&amp;rsquo;s tricks it could not withstand.&#xA;Thanks to Stephen McCamant and Kangjie Lu for hosting my visit, and everyone at University of Minnesota.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attribute Inference attacks are really Imputation</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/attribute-inference-attacks-are-really-imputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/attribute-inference-attacks-are-really-imputation/</guid>
      <description>Post by Bargav Jayaraman&#xA;Attribute inference attacks have been shown by prior works to pose privacy threat against ML models. However, these works assume the knowledge of the training distribution and we show that in such cases these attacks do no better than a data imputataion attack that does not have access to the model. We explore the attribute inference risks in the cases where the adversary has limited or no prior knowledge of the training distribution and show that our white-box attribute inference attack (that uses neuron activations to infer the unknown sensitive attribute) surpasses imputation in these data constrained cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Jayaraman!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-jayaraman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-jayaraman/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Bargav Jayaraman for successfully defending his PhD thesis!&#xA;Dr. Jayaraman and his PhD committee: Mohammad&amp;nbsp;Mahmoody, Quanquan&amp;nbsp;Gu (UCLA Department of Computer Science, on screen), Yanjun&amp;nbsp;Qi (Committee Chair, on screen), Denis&amp;nbsp;Nekipelov (Department of Economics, on screen), and David Evans Bargav will join the Meta AI Lab in Menlo Park, CA as a post-doctoral researcher.&#xA;Analyzing the Leaky Cauldron: Inference Attacks on Machine Learning Machine learning models have been shown to leak sensitive information about their training data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Tradeoffs between Fickleness and Obstinacy in NLP Models</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/balancing-tradeoffs-between-fickleness-and-obstinacy-in-nlp-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/balancing-tradeoffs-between-fickleness-and-obstinacy-in-nlp-models/</guid>
      <description>Post by Hannah Chen.&#xA;Our work on balanced adversarial training looks at how to train models that are robust to two different types of adversarial examples:&#xA;Hannah Chen, Yangfeng Ji, David Evans. Balanced Adversarial Training: Balancing Tradeoffs between Fickleness and Obstinacy in NLP Models. In The 2022 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Abu Dhabi, 7-11 December 2022. [ArXiv]&#xA;Adversarial Examples At the broadest level, an adversarial example is an input crafted intentionally to confuse a model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Submission Award at VISxAI 2022</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/best-submission-award-at-visxai-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/best-submission-award-at-visxai-2022/</guid>
      <description>Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility by Evan Rose, Fnu Suya, and David Evans won the Best Submission Award at the 5th Workshop on Visualization for AI Explainability.&#xA;Undergraduate student Evan Rose led the work and presented it at VISxAI in Oklahoma City, 17 October 2022.&#xA;Congratulations to #VISxAI&amp;#39;s Best Submission Awards:&#xA;🏆 K-Means Clustering: An Explorable Explainer by @yizhe_ang https://t.co/BULW33WPzo&#xA;🏆 Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility by Evan Rose, @suyafnu, and @UdacityDave https://t.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Poisoning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/visualizing-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/visualizing-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>How does a poisoning attack work and why are some groups more susceptible to being victimized by a poisoning attack?&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ve posted work that helps understand how poisoning attacks work with some engaging visualizations:&#xA;Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility&#xA;An Experimental Exploration on the Effectiveness of Poisoning Attacks&#xA;Evan Rose, Fnu Suya, and David Evans&#xA;Follow the link to try the interactive version! Machine learning is susceptible to poisoning attacks in which adversaries inject maliciously crafted training data into the training set to induce specific model behavior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIML: What Machine Learnt Models Reveal</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/biml-what-machine-learnt-models-reveal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/biml-what-machine-learnt-models-reveal/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk in the Berryville Institute of Machine Learning in the Barn series on What Machine Learnt Models Reveal, which is now available as an edited video:&#xA;David Evans, a professor of computer science researching security and privacy at the University of Virginia, talks about data leakage risk in ML systems and different approaches used to attack and secure models and datasets. Juxtaposing adversarial risks that target records and those aimed at attributes, David shows that differential privacy cannot capture all inference risks, and calls for more research based on privacy experiments aimed at both datasets and distributions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Zhang!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-zhang/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Xiao Zhang for successfully defending his PhD thesis!&#xA;Dr. Zhang and his PhD committee: Somesh Jha (University of Wisconsin), David Evans, Tom Fletcher; Tianxi&amp;nbsp;Li&amp;nbsp;(UVA&amp;nbsp;Statistics), David&amp;nbsp;Wu&amp;nbsp;(UT&amp;nbsp;Austin), Mohammad&amp;nbsp;Mahmoody; Xiao&amp;nbsp;Zhang. Xiao will join the CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security in Saarbrücken, Germany this fall as a tenure-track faculty member.&#xA;From Characterizing Intrinsic Robustness to Adversarially Robust Machine Learning The prevalence of adversarial examples raises questions about the reliability of machine learning systems, especially for their deployment in critical applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICLR 2022: Understanding Intrinsic Robustness Using Label Uncertainty</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2022-understanding-intrinsic-robustness-using-label-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2022-understanding-intrinsic-robustness-using-label-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>(Blog post written by Xiao Zhang)&#xA;Motivated by the empirical hardness of developing robust classifiers against adversarial perturbations, researchers began asking the question “Does there even exist a robust classifier?”. This is formulated as the intrinsic robustness problem (Mahloujifar et al., 2019), where the goal is to characterize the maximum adversarial robustness possible for a given robust classification problem. Building upon the connection between adversarial robustness and classifier’s error region, it has been shown that if we restrict the search to the set of imperfect classifiers, the intrinsic robustness problem can be reduced to the concentration of measure problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Research Summit: Surprising (and unsurprising) Inference Risks in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-research-summit-surprising-and-unsurprising-inference-risks-in-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-research-summit-surprising-and-unsurprising-inference-risks-in-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the Practical and Theoretical Privacy of Machine Learning Training Pipelines Workshop at the Microsoft Research Summit (21 October 2021):&#xA;Surprising (and Unsurprising) Inference Risks in Machine Learning [PDF] The work by Bargav Jayaraman (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) that I talked about on improving membership inference attacks is described in more details here:&#xA;Bargav Jayaraman, Lingxiao Wang, Katherine Knipmeyer, Quanquan Gu, David Evans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVA News Article</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/uva-news-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/uva-news-article/</guid>
      <description>UVA News has an article by Audra Book on our research on security and privacy of machine learning (with some very nice quotes from several students in the group, and me saying something positive about the NSA!): Computer science professor David Evans and his team conduct experiments to understand security and privacy risks associated with machine learning, 8 September 2021.&#xA;David Evans, professor of computer science in the University of Virginia School of Engineering and Applied Science, is leading research to understand how machine learning models can be compromised.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model-Targeted Poisoning Attacks with Provable Convergence</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/model-targeted-poisoning-attacks-with-provable-convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/model-targeted-poisoning-attacks-with-provable-convergence/</guid>
      <description>(Post by Sean Miller, using images adapted from Suya&amp;rsquo;s talk slides)&#xA;Data Poisoning Attacks Machine learning models are often trained using data from untrusted sources, leaving them open to poisoning attacks where adversaries use their control over a small fraction of that training data to poison the model in a particular way.&#xA;Most work on poisoning attacks is directly driven by an attacker&amp;rsquo;s objective, where the adversary chooses poisoning points that maximize some target objective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Risks of Distribution Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/on-the-risks-of-distribution-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/on-the-risks-of-distribution-inference/</guid>
      <description>(Cross-post by Anshuman Suri)&#xA;Inference attacks seek to infer sensitive information about the training process of a revealed machine-learned model, most often about the training data.&#xA;Standard inference attacks (which we call “dataset inference attacks”) aim to learn something about a particular record that may have been in that training data. For example, in a membership inference attack (Reza Shokri et al., Membership Inference Attacks Against Machine Learning Models, IEEE S&amp;amp;P 2017), the adversary aims to infer whether or not a particular record was included in the training data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Translation of MPC Book</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/chinese-translation-of-mpc-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/chinese-translation-of-mpc-book/</guid>
      <description>A Chinese translation of our A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation book (by David Evans, Vladimir Kolesnikov, and Mike Rosulek) is now available!&#xA;Thanks to Weiran Liu and Sengchao Ding for all the work they did on the translation.&#xA;To order from JD.com: https://item.jd.com/13302742.html&#xA;(The English version of the book is still available for free download, from https://securecomputation.org.)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICLR DPML 2021: Inference Risks for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-dpml-2021-inference-risks-for-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-dpml-2021-inference-risks-for-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I gave an invited talk at the Distributed and Private Machine Learning (DPML) workshop at ICLR 2021 on Inference Risks for Machine Learning.&#xA;The talk mostly covers work by Bargav Jayaraman on evaluating privacy in machine learning and connecting attribute inference and imputation, and recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Hide a Backdoor</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/how-to-hide-a-backdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/how-to-hide-a-backdoor/</guid>
      <description>The Register has an article on our recent work on Stealthy Backdoors as Compression Artifacts: Thomas Claburn, How to hide a backdoor in AI software — Neural networks can be aimed to misbehave when squeezed, The Register, 5 May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codaspy 2021 Keynote: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the 11th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy:&#xA;When Models Learn Too Much [PDF] The talk includes Bargav Jayaraman&amp;rsquo;s work (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) on evaluating privacy in machine learning, as well as more recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference attacks, and Bargav on attribute inference and imputation:&#xA;Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice “When models learn too much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrySP Talk: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/crysp-talk-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/crysp-talk-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk on When Models Learn Too Much at the University of Waterloo (virtually) in the CrySP Speaker Series on Privacy (29 March 2021):&#xA;Abstract Statistical machine learning uses training data to produce models that capture patterns in that data. When models are trained on private data, such as medical records or personal emails, there is a risk that those models not only learn the hoped-for patterns, but will also learn and expose sensitive information about their training data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Estimation of Concentration (ICLR 2021)</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/improved-estimation-of-concentration-iclr-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/improved-estimation-of-concentration-iclr-2021/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on Improved Estimation of Concentration Under ℓp-Norm Distance Metrics Using Half Spaces (Jack Prescott, Xiao Zhang, and David Evans) will be presented at ICLR 2021.&#xA;Abstract: Concentration of measure has been argued to be the fundamental cause of adversarial vulnerability. Mahloujifar et al. (2019) presented an empirical way to measure the concentration of a data distribution using samples, and employed it to find lower bounds on intrinsic robustness for several benchmark datasets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/virginia-consumer-data-protection-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/virginia-consumer-data-protection-act/</guid>
      <description>Josephine Lamp presented on the new data privacy law that is pending in Virginia (it still needs a few steps including expected signing by governor, but likely to go into effect Jan 1, 2023): Slides (PDF)&#xA;This article provides a summary of the law: Virginia Passes Consumer Privacy Law; Other States May Follow, National Law Review, 17 February 2021.&#xA;The law itself is here: SB 1392: Consumer Data Protection Act</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Accountability and the Law</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/algorithmic-accountability-and-the-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/algorithmic-accountability-and-the-law/</guid>
      <description>Brink News (a publication of The Atlantic) published an essay I co-authored with Tom Nachbar (UVA Law School) on how the law views algorithmic accountability and the limits of what measures are permitted under the law to adjust algorithms to counter inequity:&#xA;Algorithms Are Running Foul of Anti-Discrimination Law&#xA;Tom Nachbar and David Evans&#xA;Brink, 7 December 2020 Computing systems that are found to discriminate on prohibited bases, such as race or sex, are no longer surprising.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Security Data Science Colloquium: Inference Privacy in Theory and Practice</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-security-data-science-colloquium-inference-privacy-in-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-security-data-science-colloquium-inference-privacy-in-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the Microsoft Security Data Science Colloquium:&#xA;When Models Learn Too Much: Inference Privacy in Theory and Practice [PDF]&#xA;The talk is mostly about Bargav Jayaraman&amp;rsquo;s work (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) on evaluating privacy:&#xA;Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fact-checking Donald Trump’s tweet firing Christopher Krebs</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/fact-checking-donald-trumps-tweet-firing-christopher-krebs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/fact-checking-donald-trumps-tweet-firing-christopher-krebs/</guid>
      <description>I was a source for thie &amp;ldquo;Pants on Fire!&amp;rdquo; fact check by PolitiFact on Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s tweet that fired Christopher Krebs claiming that &amp;ldquo;The recent statement by Chris Krebs on the security of the 2020 Election was highly inaccurate, in that there were massive improprieties and fraud - including dead people voting, Poll Watchers not allowed into polling locations, “glitches” in the voting machines which changed&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&#xA;PolitiFact: Fact-checking Donald Trump’s tweet firing Christopher Krebs, 18 November 2020</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voting Security</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/voting-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/voting-security/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed for a local news story by Daniel Grimes on election security: UVA cybersecurity expert: Virginia is one of the safer states to cast a ballot, NBC 29 News, 21 October 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/merlin-morgan-and-the-importance-of-thresholds-and-priors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/merlin-morgan-and-the-importance-of-thresholds-and-priors/</guid>
      <description>Post by Katherine Knipmeyer&#xA;Machine learning poses a substantial risk that adversaries will be able to discover information that the model does not intend to reveal. One set of methods by which consumers can learn this sensitive information, known broadly as membership inference attacks, predicts whether or not a query record belongs to the training set. A basic membership inference attack involves an attacker with a given record and black-box access to a model who tries to determine whether said record was a member of the model’s training set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversarially Robust Representations</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/robustrepresentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/robustrepresentations/</guid>
      <description>Post by Sicheng Zhu&#xA;With the rapid development of deep learning and the explosive growth of unlabeled data, representation learning is becoming increasingly important. It has made impressive applications such as pre-trained language models (e.g., BERT and GPT-3).&#xA;Popular as it is, representation learning raises concerns about the robustness of learned representations under adversarial settings. For example, how can we compare the robustness to different representations, and how can we build representations that enable robust downstream classifiers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Robustness using Conditional GANs</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/intrinsic-robustness-using-conditional-gans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/intrinsic-robustness-using-conditional-gans/</guid>
      <description>The video of Xiao&amp;rsquo;s presentation for AISTATS 2020 is now available: Understanding the Intrinsic Robustness of Image Distributions using Conditional Generative Models&#xA;Starting with Gilmer et al. (2018), several works have demonstrated the inevitability of adversarial examples based on different assumptions about the underlying input probability space. It remains unclear, however, whether these results apply to natural image distributions. In this work, we assume the underlying data distribution is captured by some conditional generative model, and prove intrinsic robustness bounds for a general class of classifiers, which solves an open problem in Fawzi et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Batch Attacks at USENIX Security 2020</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/hybrid-batch-attacks-at-usenix-security-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/hybrid-batch-attacks-at-usenix-security-2020/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the video for Suya&amp;rsquo;s presentation on Hybrid Batch Attacks at USENIX Security 2020:&#xA;Download Video [mp4]&#xA;Blog Post&#xA;Paper: [PDF] [arXiv]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pointwise Paraphrase Appraisal is Potentially Problematic</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/pointwise-paraphrase-appraisal-is-potentially-problematic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/pointwise-paraphrase-appraisal-is-potentially-problematic/</guid>
      <description>Hannah Chen presented her paper on Pointwise Paraphrase Appraisal is Potentially Problematic at the ACL 2020 Student Research Workshop:&#xA;The prevailing approach for training and evaluating paraphrase identification models is constructed as a binary classification problem: the model is given a pair of sentences, and is judged by how accurately it classifies pairs as either paraphrases or non-paraphrases. This pointwise-based evaluation method does not match well the objective of most real world applications, so the goal of our work is to understand how models which perform well under pointwise evaluation may fail in practice and find better methods for evaluating paraphrase identification models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Naming the Blog</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/de-naming-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/de-naming-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>This blog was started in January 2008, a bit over eight years after I started as a professor at UVA and initiated the research group. It was named after Thomas Jefferson&amp;rsquo;s cipher wheel, which has long been (and remains) one of my favorite ways to introduce cryptography.&#xA;Figuring out how to honor our history, including Jefferson&amp;rsquo;s founding of the University, and appreciate his ideals and enormous contributions, while confronting the reality of Jefferson as a slave owner and abuser, will be a challenge and responsibility for people above my administrative rank.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oakland Test-of-Time Awards</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/oakland-test-of-time-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/oakland-test-of-time-awards/</guid>
      <description>I chaired the committee to select Test-of-Time Awards for the IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy symposia from 1995-2006, which were presented at the Opening Section of the 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips2019/</guid>
      <description> Here&#39;s a video of Xiao Zhang&#39;s presentation at NeurIPS 2019: https://slideslive.com/38921718/track-2-session-1 (starting at 26:50) See this post for info on the paper. Here are a few pictures from NeurIPS 2019 (by Sicheng Zhu and Mohammad Mahmoody): </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USENIX Security 2020: Hybrid Batch Attacks</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2020-hybrid-batch-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2020-hybrid-batch-attacks/</guid>
      <description>New: Video Presentation&#xA;Finding Black-box Adversarial Examples with Limited Queries Black-box attacks generate adversarial examples (AEs) against deep neural networks with only API access to the victim model.&#xA;Existing black-box attacks can be grouped into two main categories:&#xA;Transfer Attacks use white-box attacks on local models to find candidate adversarial examples that transfer to the target model.&#xA;Optimization Attacks use queries to the target model and apply optimization techniques to search for adversarial examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2019: Empirically Measuring Concentration</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2019-empirically-measuring-concentration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2019-empirically-measuring-concentration/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang will present our work (with Saeed Mahloujifar and Mohamood Mahmoody) as a spotlight at NeurIPS 2019, Vancouver, 10 December 2019.&#xA;Recent theoretical results, starting with Gilmer et al.&amp;rsquo;s Adversarial Spheres (2018), show that if inputs are drawn from a concentrated metric probability space, then adversarial examples with small perturbation are inevitable.c The key insight from this line of research is that concentration of measure gives lower bound on adversarial risk for a large collection of classifiers (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White House Visit</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/white-house-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/white-house-visit/</guid>
      <description>I had a chance to visit the White House for a Roundtable on Accelerating Responsible Sharing of Federal Data. The meeting was held under &amp;ldquo;Chatham House Rules&amp;rdquo;, so I won&amp;rsquo;t mention the other participants here.&#xA;The meeting was held in the Roosevelt Room of the White House. We entered through the visitor&amp;rsquo;s side entrance. After a security gate (where you put your phone in a lockbox, so no pictures inside) with a TV blaring Fox News, there is a pleasant lobby for waiting, and then an entrance right into the Roosevelt Room.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jobs for Humans, 2029-2059</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/jobs-for-humans-2029-2059/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/jobs-for-humans-2029-2059/</guid>
      <description>I was honored to particilate in a panel at an event on Adult Education in the Age of Artificial Intelligence that was run by The Great Courses as a fundraiser for the Academy of Hope, an adult public charter school in Washington, D.C.&#xA;I spoke first, following a few introductory talks, and was followed by Nicole Smith and Ellen Scully-Russ, and a keynote from Dexter Manley, Super Bowl winner with the Washington Redskins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Symposium Posters</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/research-symposium-posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/research-symposium-posters/</guid>
      <description>Five students from our group presented posters at the department&amp;rsquo;s Fall Research Symposium:&#xA;Anshuman Suri&#39;s Overview Talk Bargav Jayaraman, Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning In Practice [</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cantor&#39;s (No Longer) Lost Proof</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cantors-no-longer-lost-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cantors-no-longer-lost-proof/</guid>
      <description>In preparing to cover Cantor&amp;rsquo;s proof of different infinite set cardinalities (one of my all-time favorite topics!) in our theory of computation course, I found various conflicting accounts of what Cantor originally proved. So, I figured it would be easy to search the web to find the original proof.&#xA;Shockingly, at least as far as I could find1, it didn&amp;rsquo;t exist on the web! The closest I could find was in Google Books the 1892 volume of the Jähresbericht Deutsche Mathematiker-Vereinigung (which many of the references pointed to), but in fact not the first value of that journal which contains the actual proof.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSAD Trustworthy Machine Learning Mini-Course</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/fosad2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/fosad2019/</guid>
      <description>I taught a mini-course on Trustworthy Machine Learning at the 19th International School on Foundations of Security Analysis and Design in Bertinoro, Italy.&#xA;Slides from my three (two-hour) lectures are posted below, along with some links to relevant papers and resources.&#xA;Class 1: Introduction/Attacks The PDF malware evasion attack is described in this paper:&#xA;Weilin Xu, Yanjun Qi, and David Evans. Automatically Evading Classifiers: A Case Study on PDF Malware Classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/evaluating-differentially-private-machine-learning-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/evaluating-differentially-private-machine-learning-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>(Cross-post by Bargav Jayaraman)&#xA;With the recent advances in composition of differential private mechanisms, the research community has been able to achieve meaningful deep learning with privacy budgets in single digits. Rènyi differential privacy (RDP) is one mechanism that provides tighter composition which is widely used because of its implementation in TensorFlow Privacy (recently, Gaussian differential privacy (GDP) has shown a tighter analysis for low privacy budgets, but it was not yet available when we did this work).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USENIX Security Symposium 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-symposium-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-symposium-2019/</guid>
      <description>Bargav Jayaraman presented our paper on Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice at the 28th USENIX Security Symposium in Santa Clara, California.&#xA;Summary by Lea Kissner:&#xA;Hey it&amp;#39;s the results! pic.twitter.com/ru1FbkESho&#xA;&amp;mdash; Lea Kissner (@LeaKissner) August 17, 2019 Also, great to see several UVA folks at the conference including:&#xA;Sam Havron (BSCS 2017, now a PhD student at Cornell) presented a paper on the work he and his colleagues have done on computer security for victims of intimate partner violence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Security and Privacy Workshop</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/google-security-and-privacy-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/google-security-and-privacy-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I presented a short talk at a workshop at Google on Adversarial ML: Closing Gaps between Theory and Practice (mostly fun for the movie of me trying to solve Google&amp;rsquo;s CAPTCHA on the last slide):&#xA;Getting the actual screencast to fit into the limited time for this talk challenged the limits of my video editing skills.&#xA;I can say with some confidence, Google does donuts much better than they do cookies!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brink Essay: AI Systems Are Complex and Fragile. Here Are Four Key Risks to Understand.</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/brink-essay-ai-systems-are-complex-and-fragile.-here-are-four-key-risks-to-understand./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/brink-essay-ai-systems-are-complex-and-fragile.-here-are-four-key-risks-to-understand./</guid>
      <description>Brink News (a publication of The Atlantic) published my essay on the risks of deploying AI systems.&#xA;Artificial intelligence technologies have the potential to transform society in positive and powerful ways. Recent studies have shown computing systems that can outperform humans at numerous once-challenging tasks, ranging from performing medical diagnoses and reviewing legal contracts to playing Go and recognizing human emotions. Despite these successes, AI systems are fundamentally fragile — and the ways they can fail are poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Federated Privacy 2019: The Dragon in the Room</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/google-federated-privacy-2019-the-dragon-in-the-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/google-federated-privacy-2019-the-dragon-in-the-room/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from a very interesting Workshop on Federated Learning and Analytics that was organized by Peter Kairouz and Brendan McMahan from Google&amp;rsquo;s federated learning team and was held at Google Seattle.&#xA;For the first part of my talk, I covered Bargav&amp;rsquo;s work on evaluating differentially private machine learning, but I reserved the last few minutes of my talk to address the cognitive dissonance I felt being at a Google meeting on privacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduation 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/graduation-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/graduation-2019/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI could save lives without spilling medical secrets</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/how-ai-could-save-lives-without-spilling-medical-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/how-ai-could-save-lives-without-spilling-medical-secrets/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m quoted in this article by Will Knight focused on the work Oasis Labs (Dawn Song&amp;rsquo;s company) is doing on privacy-preserving medical data analysis: How AI could save lives without spilling medical secrets, MIT Technology Review, 14 May 2019.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The whole notion of doing computation while keeping data secret is an incredibly powerful one,&amp;rdquo; says David Evans, who specializes in machine learning and security at the University of Virginia. When applied across hospitals and patient populations, for instance, machine learning might unlock completely new ways of tying disease to genomics, test results, and other patient information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost-Sensitive Adversarial Robustness at ICLR 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cost-sensitive-adversarial-robustness-at-iclr-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cost-sensitive-adversarial-robustness-at-iclr-2019/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang will present Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples on May 7 (4:30-6:30pm) at ICLR 2019 in New Orleans.&#xA;Paper: [PDF] [OpenReview] [ArXiv]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empirically Measuring Concentration</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/empirically-measuring-concentration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/empirically-measuring-concentration/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang and Saeed Mahloujifar will present our work on Empirically Measuring Concentration: Fundamental Limits on Intrinsic Robustness at two workshops May 6 at ICLR 2019 in New Orleans: Debugging Machine Learning Models and Safe Machine Learning: Specification, Robustness and Assurance.&#xA;Paper: [PDF]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SRG Lunch</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/srg-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/srg-lunch/</guid>
      <description>Some photos for our lunch to celebrate the end of semester, beginning of summer, and congratulate Weilin Xu on his PhD:&#xA;Left to right: Jonah&amp;nbsp;Weissman, Yonghwi&amp;nbsp; Kown, Bargav&amp;nbsp;Jayaraman, Aihua&amp;nbsp;Chen, Hannah&amp;nbsp;Chen, Weilin&amp;nbsp;Xu, Riley&amp;nbsp;Spahn, David&amp;nbsp;Evans, Fnu&amp;nbsp;Suya, Yuan&amp;nbsp;Tian, Mainuddin&amp;nbsp;Jonas, Tu&amp;nbsp;Le, Faysal&amp;nbsp;Hossain, Xiao&amp;nbsp;Zhang, Jack&amp;nbsp;Verrier </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JASON Spring Meeting: Adversarial Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/jason-spring-meeting-adversarial-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/jason-spring-meeting-adversarial-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege of speaking at the JASON Spring Meeting, undoubtably one of the most diverse meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve been part of with talks on hypersonic signatures (from my DSSG 2008-2009 colleague, Ian Boyd), FBI DNA, nuclear proliferation in Iran, engineering biological materials, and the 2020 census (including a very interesting presentatino from John Abowd on the differential privacy mechanisms they have developed and evaluated). (Unfortunately, my lack of security clearance kept me out of the SCIF used for the talks on quantum computing and more sensitive topics).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Dr. Xu!</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/congratulations-dr.-xu/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Weilin Xu for successfully defending his PhD Thesis!&#xA;Weilin&#39;s Committee: Homa Alemzadeh, Yanjun Qi, Patrick McDaniel (on screen), David Evans, Vicente Ordóñez Román Improving Robustness of Machine Learning Models using Domain Knowledge Although machine learning techniques have achieved great success in many areas, such as computer vision, natural language processing, and computer security, recent studies have shown that they are not robust under attack. A motivated adversary is often able to craft input samples that force a machine learning model to produce incorrect predictions, even if the target model achieves high accuracy on normal test inputs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Plan to Eradicate Stalkerware</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/a-plan-to-eradicate-stalkerware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/a-plan-to-eradicate-stalkerware/</guid>
      <description>Sam Havron (BSCS 2017) is quoted in an article in Wired on eradicating stalkerware:&#xA;The full extent of that stalkerware crackdown will only prove out with time and testing, says Sam Havron, a Cornell researcher who worked on last year&amp;rsquo;s spyware study. Much more work remains. He notes that domestic abuse victims can also be tracked with dual-use apps often overlooked by antivirus firms, like antitheft software Cerberus. Even innocent tools like Apple&amp;rsquo;s Find My Friends and Google Maps&amp;rsquo; location-sharing features can be abused if they don&amp;rsquo;t better communicate to users that they may have been secretly configured to share their location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISMR 2019: Context-aware Monitoring in Robotic Surgery</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/ismr-2019-context-aware-monitoring-in-robotic-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/ismr-2019-context-aware-monitoring-in-robotic-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Samin Yasar presented our paper on Context-award Monitoring in Robotic Surgery at the 2019 International Symposium on Medical Robotics (ISMR) in Atlanta, Georgia.&#xA;Robotic-assisted minimally invasive surgery (MIS) has enabled procedures with increased precision and dexterity, but surgical robots are still open loop and require surgeons to work with a tele-operation console providing only limited visual feedback. In this setting, mechanical failures, software faults, or human errors might lead to adverse events resulting in patient complications or fatalities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Fools</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/deep-fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/deep-fools/</guid>
      <description>New Electronics has an article that includes my Deep Learning and Security Workshop talk: Deep fools, 21 January 2019.&#xA;A better version of the image Mainuddin Jonas produced that they use (which they screenshot from the talk video) is below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markets, Mechanisms, Machines</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/markets-mechanisms-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/markets-mechanisms-machines/</guid>
      <description>My course for Spring 2019 is Markets, Mechanisms, Machines, cross-listed as cs4501/econ4559 and co-taught with Denis Nekipelov. The course will explore interesting connections between economics and computer science.&#xA;My qualifications for being listed as instructor for a 4000-level Economics course are limited to taking an introductory microeconomics course my first year as an undergraduate.&#xA;Its good to finally get a chance to redeem myself for giving up on Economics 28 years ago!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICLR 2019: Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2019-cost-sensitive-robustness-against-adversarial-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2019-cost-sensitive-robustness-against-adversarial-examples/</guid>
      <description>Xiao Zhang and my paper on Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples has been accepted to ICLR 2019.&#xA;Several recent works have developed methods for training classifiers that are certifiably robust against norm-bounded adversarial perturbations. However, these methods assume that all the adversarial transformations provide equal value for adversaries, which is seldom the case in real-world applications. We advocate for cost-sensitive robustness as the criteria for measuring the classifier&amp;rsquo;s performance for specific tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation, co-authored with Vladimir Kolesnikov and Mike Rosulek, is now published by Now Publishers in their Foundations and Trends in Privacy and Security series.&#xA;You can download the book for free (we retain the copyright and are allowed to post an open version) from securecomputation.org, or buy an PDF version from the published for $260 (there is also a printed $99 version).&#xA;Secure multi-party computation (MPC) has evolved from a theoretical curiosity in the 1980s to a tool for building real systems today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2018: Distributed Learning without Distress</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</guid>
      <description>Bargav Jayaraman presented our work on privacy-preserving machine learning at the 32nd Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2018) in Montreal.&#xA;Distributed learning (sometimes known as federated learning) allows a group of independent data owners to collaboratively learn a model over their data sets without exposing their private data. Our approach combines differential privacy with secure multi-party computation to both protect the data during training and produce a model that provides privacy against inference attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Machine Learning Ever Be Trustworthy?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/can-machine-learning-ever-be-trustworthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/can-machine-learning-ever-be-trustworthy/</guid>
      <description>I gave the Booz Allen Hamilton Distinguished Colloquium at the University of Maryland on Can Machine Learning Ever Be Trustworthy?.&#xA;[Video](https://vid.umd.edu/detsmediasite/Play/e8009558850944bfb2cac477f8d741711d?catalog=74740199-303c-49a2-9025-2dee0a195650) &amp;middot; [SpeakerDeck](https://speakerdeck.com/evansuva/can-machine-learning-ever-be-trustworthy) Abstract Machine learning has produced extraordinary results over the past few years, and machine learning systems are rapidly being deployed for critical tasks, even in adversarial environments. This talk will survey some of the reasons building trustworthy machine learning systems is inherently impossible, and dive into some recent research on adversarial examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center for Trustworthy Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/center-for-trustworthy-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/center-for-trustworthy-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>The National Science Foundation announced the Center for Trustworthy Machine Learning today, a new five-year SaTC Frontier Center &amp;ldquo;to develop a rigorous understanding of the security risks of the use of machine learning and to devise the tools, metrics and methods to manage and mitigate security vulnerabilities.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The Center is lead by Patrick McDaniel at Penn State University, and in addition to our group, includes Dan Boneh and Percy Liang (Stanford University), Kamalika Chaudhuri (University of California San Diego), Somesh Jha (University of Wisconsin) and Dawn Song (University of California Berkeley).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence: the new ghost in the machine</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/artificial-intelligence-the-new-ghost-in-the-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/artificial-intelligence-the-new-ghost-in-the-machine/</guid>
      <description>Engineering and Technology Magazine (a publication of the British [Institution of Engineering and Technology]() has an article that highlights adversarial machine learning research: Artificial intelligence: the new ghost in the machine, 10 October 2018, by Chris Edwards.&#xA;Although researchers such as David Evans of the University of Virginia see a full explanation being a little way off in the future, the massive number of parameters encoded by DNNs and the avoidance of overtraining due to SGD may have an answer to why the networks can hallucinate images and, as a result, see things that are not there and ignore those that are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violations of Children’s Privacy Laws</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/violations-of-childrens-privacy-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/violations-of-childrens-privacy-laws/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times has an article, How Game Apps That Captivate Kids Have Been Collecting Their Data about a lawsuit the state of New Mexico is bringing against app markets (including Google) that allow apps presented as being for children in the Play store to violate COPPA rules and mislead users into tracking children. The lawsuit stems from a study led by Serge Egleman’s group at UC Berkeley that analyzed COPPA violations in children’s apps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USENIX Security 2018</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-2018/</guid>
      <description>Three SRG posters were presented at USENIX Security Symposium 2018 in Baltimore, Maryland:&#xA;Nathaniel Grevatt (GDPR-Compliant Data Processing: Improving Pseudonymization with Multi-Party Computation) Matthew Wallace and Parvesh Samayamanthula (Deceiving Privacy Policy Classifiers with Adversarial Examples) Guy Verrier (How is GDPR Affecting Privacy Policies?, joint with Haonan Chen and Yuan Tian) There were also a surprising number of appearances by an unidentified unicorn:&#xA;Your poster may have made the cut for the #usesec18 Poster Reception, but has it received the approval of a tiny, adorable unicorn?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mutually Assured Destruction and the Impending AI Apocalypse</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/mutually-assured-destruction-and-the-impending-ai-apocalypse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/mutually-assured-destruction-and-the-impending-ai-apocalypse/</guid>
      <description>I gave a keynote talk at USENIX Workshop of Offensive Technologies, Baltimore, Maryland, 13 August 2018. The title and abstract are what I provided for the WOOT program, but unfortunately (or maybe fortunately for humanity!) I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to actually figure out a talk to match the title and abstract I provided.&#xA;The history of security includes a long series of arms races, where a new technology emerges and is subsequently developed and exploited by both defenders and attackers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Summer Camp</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cybersecurity-summer-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cybersecurity-summer-camp/</guid>
      <description>I helped organize a summer camp for high school teachers focused on cybersecurity, led by Ahmed Ibrahim. Some of the materials from the camp on cryptography, including the Jefferson Wheel and visual cryptography are here: Cipher School for Muggles.&#xA;Cybersecurity Goes to Summer Camp. UVA Today. 22 July 2018. [archive.org]&#xA;Earlier this week, 25 high school teachers – including 21 from Virginia – filled a glass-walled room in Rice Hall, sitting in high adjustable chairs at wheeled work tables, their laptops open, following a lecture with graphics about the dangers that lurk in cyberspace and trying to figure out how to pass the information on to a generation that seems to share the most intimate details of life online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependable and Secure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/dependable-and-secure-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/dependable-and-secure-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I co-organized, with Homa Alemzadeh and Karthik Pattabiraman, a workshop on trustworthy machine learning attached to DSN 2018, in Luxembourg: DSML: Dependable and Secure Machine Learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DLS Keynote: Is &#39;adversarial examples&#39; an Adversarial Example?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/dls-keynote-is-adversarial-examples-an-adversarial-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/dls-keynote-is-adversarial-examples-an-adversarial-example/</guid>
      <description>I gave a keynote talk at the 1st Deep Learning and Security Workshop (co-located with the 39th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy). San Francisco, California. 24 May 2018&#xA;Abstract&#xA;Over the past few years, there has been an explosion of research in security of machine learning and on adversarial examples in particular. Although this is in many ways a new and immature research area, the general problem of adversarial examples has been a core problem in information security for thousands of years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wahoos at Oakland</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/wahoos-at-oakland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/wahoos-at-oakland/</guid>
      <description>UVA Group Dinner at IEEE Security and Privacy 2018 Including our newest faculty member, Yongwhi Kwon, joining UVA in Fall 2018!&#xA;Yuan Tian, Fnu Suya, Mainuddin Jonas, Yongwhi Kwon, David Evans, Weihang Wang, Aihua&amp;nbsp;Chen,&amp;nbsp;Weilin&amp;nbsp;Xu&#xA;## Poster Session Fnu Suya (with Yuan Tian and David Evans), Adversaries Don’t Care About Averages: Batch Attacks on Black-Box Classifiers [PDF] Mainuddin Jonas (with David Evans), Enhancing Adversarial Example Defenses Using Internal Layers [PDF] </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Last 3000 Years of Adversarial Examples</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/lessons-from-the-last-3000-years-of-adversarial-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/lessons-from-the-last-3000-years-of-adversarial-examples/</guid>
      <description>I spoke on Lessons from the Last 3000 Years of Adversarial Examples at Huawei’s Strategy and Technology Workshop in Shenzhen, China, 15 May 2018. We also got to tour Huawei&amp;#8217;s new research and development campus, under construction about 40 minutes from Shenzhen. It is pretty close to Disneyland, with its own railroad and villages themed after different European cities (Paris, Bologna, etc.).&#xA;Huawei&amp;#8217;s New Research and Development Campus [More Pictures]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Squeezing at NDSS</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/feature-squeezing-at-ndss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/feature-squeezing-at-ndss/</guid>
      <description>Weilin Xu presented Feature Squeezing: Detecting Adversarial Examples in Deep Neural Networks at the Network and Distributed System Security Symposium 2018. San Diego, CA. 21 February 2018.&#xA;Paper: Weilin Xu, David Evans, Yanjun Qi. Feature Squeezing: Detecting Adversarial Examples in Deep Neural Networks. NDSS 2018. [PDF]&#xA;Project Site: EvadeML.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Older Posts</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/older-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/older-posts/</guid>
      <description>Older posts have not been moved into this new blog, but are still available here:&#xA;2017 2016 2015 2014 2013 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/advml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/advml/</guid>
      <description>Adversarial Machine Learning Study Group Meetings on Mondays, 11am (Summer 2020)&#xA;Leaders: Hannah Chen, Anshuman Suri&#xA;DateTopic/Talk 25 May 2020 Nicolas Carlini, Lessons Learned from Evaluating the Robustness of Defenses to Adversarial Examples (USENIX Security 2019) 1 June 2020 Aleksander Madry, A New Perspective on Adversarial Perturbations (Simons Institute, July 2019) 8 June 2020 Sadia Afroz, How to Build Realistic Machine Learning Systems for Security? (USENIX Enigma 2020)&#xA;Ji Gao, Black-box Generation of Adversarial Text Sequences to Evade Deep Learning Classifiers (Deep Learning and Security Workshop 2018) 15 June 2020 (Joint with Privacy Study Group) Mathias Lécuyer, Certified Robustness to Adversarial Examples with Differential Privacy (IEEE Security and Privacy 2019)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/awards/</guid>
      <description>This page collects awards won by SRG students and alumni.&#xA;National Awards CRA Outstanding Undergraduate Researchers The CRA Outstanding Undergraduate Researchers Award is the premier national research award that recognized undergraduate research in Computer Science, given to students at North American universities by the Computing Research Association.&#xA;Jonathan Burket (BACS 2013, CMU PhD program), 2013&amp;nbsp;Honorable Mention Peter Chapman (BACS 2012, CMU PhD program), 2012&amp;nbsp;Runner-Up Jiamin Chen (BACS 2012, now at UCLA), 2012 Honorable Mention Rachel Lathbury (BACS 2010, now at University of Pennsylvania), 2010&amp;nbsp;Honorable&amp;nbsp;Mention Adriana Felt (BSCS 2008, UC Berkeley PhD 2012, now at Google), 2008&amp;nbsp;Finalist Salvatore Guarnieri (BSCS 2006, now at IBM and University of Washington), 2006&amp;nbsp;Finalist Ami Malaviya (BSCS 2005), 2005&amp;nbsp;Honorable&amp;nbsp;Mention Jonathan McCune (BSCS 2003, CMU PhD 2009), 2003&amp;nbsp;Honorable&amp;nbsp;Mention NSF Graduate Research Fellowships The National Science Foundation’s Graduate Research Fellowships recognize outstanding graduate students and provides up to three years of funding to support a student’s graduate work (over $100,000 total).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/bat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/bat/</guid>
      <description>Balanced Adversarial Training Balancing Tradeoffs between Fickleness and Obstinacy in NLP Models Hannah Chen, Yangfeng Ji, David Evans&#xA;In The 2022 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Abu Dhabi, 7-11 December 2022&#xA;Adversarial Examples At the broadest level, an adversarial example is an input crafted intentionally to confuse a model. However, most work focus on the defintion as an input constructed by applying a small perturbation that preserves the ground truth label but changes model&amp;rsquo;s output (Goodfellow et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/gpuservers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/gpuservers/</guid>
      <description>Using the GPU Servers Here are some notes on how to use the GPU servers (thanks to Brian Tran for creating this document). Before getting started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a CS department account set up.&#xA;First, log into the general purpose server (e.g., portal01) using: ssh -l _YourComputingID_ portal01.cs.virginia.edu (for more, see https://www.cs.virginia.edu/wiki/doku.php?id=linux_ssh_access.&#xA;Run srun -p gpu -w _ai01_ --pty bash -i -l to log into one of the nodes that support GPU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/poisoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!doctype html&gt; Poisoning Attacks and Subpopulation Susceptibility An Experimental Exploration on the Effectiveness of Poisoning Attacks&#xA;Evan Rose University of Virginia Fnu Suya David Evans 5th Workshop on Visualization for AI Explainability VISxAI&#xA;21 September 2022&#xA;Class Separation α = 1.00 Random Label Fraction β = 0.00 Dataset seed Poisoning algorithm: Manual Label flip Model-targeted Label: Tool: Machine learning is susceptible to poisoning attacks in which adversaries inject maliciously crafted training data into the training set to induce specific model behavior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Privacy Our research focuses on understanding and mitigating privacy risks associated with machine learning. This includes both data privacy (protecting sensitive data used to train a model during the collection and learning process) and inference privacy (limiting what can be inferred about sensitive training data from an exposed model).&#xA;Privacy Reading Group&#xA;Inference Privacy These blog posts (in forward chronological order) summarize our recent work on evaluating inference leakage from models:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/privacyreadinggroup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/privacyreadinggroup/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Reading Group Meetings on Tuesdays, 11am (Summer 2020)&#xA;Leader: Bargav Jayaraman&#xA;DateTopic/Talk 26 May 2020 Cynthia Dwork, Privacy-Preserving Data Analysis (Alan Turing Institute, Turing Lecture, Dec 2016) 2 June 2020 Guy Rothblum, Composition: The Key to Differential Privacy is Success (Institute for Advanced Study, Nov 2016) 9 June 2020 Yuxin Wang, Detecting Violations of Differential Privacy (ACM CCS 2018)&#xA;Benjamin Bichsel, DP-Finder: Finding Differential Privacy Violations by Sampling and Optimization (ACM CCS 2018)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/prospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/prospective/</guid>
      <description>Advice for Prospective Research Students Like most professors, I get several hundred emails a year from prospective students interested in coming to our university for graduate school and joining my research group. I try to reply to all messages that are not obviously spam, but find most messages I receive make me less likely to want to accept the students sending them.&#xA;This page provides some advice for prospective grad school applicants considering emailing me, but most of it probably applies to any other professor you want to contact also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/scriptinspector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/scriptinspector/</guid>
      <description>ScriptInspector: Monitoring Embedded Web Scripts Modern web applications make frequent use of third-party scripts, often in ways that allow scripts loaded from external servers to make unrestricted changes to the embedding page and access citical resources including private user information.&#xA;ScriptInspector assists site administrators in understanding, monitoring, and restricting the behavior of third-party scripts embedded in their site. ScriptInspector is a modified browser that can intercept, record, and check third-party script accesses to critical resources against security policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/studygroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/studygroups/</guid>
      <description>Active Study Groups Groups meet on zoom, and everyone is welcome.&#xA;Summer 2021 we will have meetings most Fridays at 9:30am (Charlottesville time), and be discussing a variety of security and privacy and related research papers.&#xA;Previous Study Groups and Seminars Adversarial Machine Learning (Summer 2020)&#xA;Leaders: Hannah Chen, Anshuman Suri&#xA;Schedule and Topics&#xA;Privacy (Summer 2020) Leader: Bargav Jayaraman&#xA;Schedule and Topics&#xA;How will Artificial Intelligence Change Humanity? (Fall 2018)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/team/</guid>
      <description>PhD Students Yu-Han (Hannah) Chen&#xA;Co-advised with Yangfeng Ji&#xA;Since Fall 2019&#xA;natural language processing&#xA;Michael Jerge&#xA;Since Jan-24&#xA;LLM reliability&#xA;Elena (Minjun) Long&#xA;Since Fall 2022&#xA;privacy of ad ecosystem&#xA;Masters Student Archit Uniyal&#xA;Since Fall 2022&#xA;privacy for NLP&#xA;Undergraduate Researchers Shinjini Bose&#xA;Undergraduate Researcher&#xA;Since Spring 2024&#xA;LLM fairness&#xA;Zihan Mei&#xA;Undergraduate Researcher&#xA;Since Spring 2024&#xA;LLM application privacy&#xA;Security Research Group Leap Day Lunch (29&amp;nbsp;February&amp;nbsp;2024)&#xA;Anshuman&amp;nbsp;Suri, Archit&amp;nbsp;Uniyal, Minjun&amp;nbsp;Long, Michael Jerge, Hannah&amp;nbsp;Chen, Josephine&amp;nbsp;Lamp Director David Evans</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/videos/</guid>
      <description>Videos Here are some selected videos of talks about our research.&#xA;Inference Risks for Machine Learning Invited talk at the Distributed and Private Machine Learning (DPML) workshop at ICLR 2021, 7 May 2021. [Video]&#xA;When Models Learn Too Much CrySP Speaker Series on Privacy, University of Waterloo, 29 March 2021. [Abstract] [Video]&#xA;Hybrid Batch Attacks Suya&amp;rsquo;s presentation on Hybrid Batch Attacks at USENIX Security 2020:&#xA;(Download Video [mp4], Blog Post, Paper: [PDF] [arXiv])</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Research Group</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/main/</guid>
      <description>Security and Privacy Research at the University of Virginia Our research seeks to empower individuals and organizations to control how their data is used. We use techniques from cryptography, programming languages, machine learning, operating systems, and other areas to both understand and improve the privacy and security of computing as practiced today, and as envisioned in the future. A major current focus is on adversarial machine learning. SRG Leap Day Lunch (29&amp;nbsp;February&amp;nbsp;2024) Anshuman&amp;nbsp;Suri, Archit&amp;nbsp;Uniyal, Minjun&amp;nbsp;Long, Michael Jerge, Hannah&amp;nbsp;Chen, Josephine&amp;nbsp;Lamp We are part of the NSF AI Institute for Agent-based Cyber Threat Intelligence and Operation (ACTION) which seeks to change the way mission-critical systems are protected against sophisticated security threats.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
