<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>papers on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/categories/papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in papers on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/categories/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SoK: Let the Privacy Games Begin! A Unified Treatment of Data Inference Privacy in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-let-the-privacy-games-begin-a-unified-treatment-of-data-inference-privacy-in-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/sok-let-the-privacy-games-begin-a-unified-treatment-of-data-inference-privacy-in-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on the use of cryptographic-style games to model inference privacy is published in IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland):
 Ahmed Salem, Giovanni Cherubin, , Boris Köpf, Andrew Paverd, Anshuman Suri, Shruti Tople, and Santiago Zanella-Béguelin. SoK: Let the Privacy Games Begin! A Unified Treatment of Data Inference Privacy in Machine Learning. IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, 2023. [Arxiv]    Tired of diverse definitions of machine learning privacy risks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVPR 2023: Manipulating Transfer Learning for Property Inference</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/cvpr-2023-manipulating-transfer-learning-for-property-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/cvpr-2023-manipulating-transfer-learning-for-property-inference/</guid>
      <description>Manipulating Transfer Learning for Property Inference Transfer learning is a popular method to train deep learning models efficiently. By reusing parameters from upstream pre-trained models, the downstream trainer can use fewer computing resources to train downstream models, compared to training models from scratch.
The figure below shows the typical process of transfer learning for vision tasks:
   However, the nature of transfer learning can be exploited by a malicious upstream trainer, leading to severe risks to the downstream trainer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribute Inference attacks are really Imputation</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/attribute-inference-attacks-are-really-imputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/attribute-inference-attacks-are-really-imputation/</guid>
      <description>Post by Bargav Jayaraman
Attribute inference attacks have been shown by prior works to pose privacy threat against ML models. However, these works assume the knowledge of the training distribution and we show that in such cases these attacks do no better than a data imputataion attack that does not have access to the model. We explore the attribute inference risks in the cases where the adversary has limited or no prior knowledge of the training distribution and show that our white-box attribute inference attack (that uses neuron activations to infer the unknown sensitive attribute) surpasses imputation in these data constrained cases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
