<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>secure computation on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/secure-computation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in secure computation on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/secure-computation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Translation of MPC Book</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/chinese-translation-of-mpc-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/chinese-translation-of-mpc-book/</guid>
      <description>A Chinese translation of our A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation book (by David Evans, Vladimir Kolesnikov, and Mike Rosulek) is now available!
   Thanks to Weiran Liu and Sengchao Ding for all the work they did on the translation.
To order from JD.com: https://item.jd.com/13302742.html
(The English version of the book is still available for free download, from https://securecomputation.org.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation, co-authored with Vladimir Kolesnikov and Mike Rosulek, is now published by Now Publishers in their Foundations and Trends in Privacy and Security series.
You can download the book for free (we retain the copyright and are allowed to post an open version) from securecomputation.org, or buy an PDF version from the published for $260 (there is also a printed $99 version).
Secure multi-party computation (MPC) has evolved from a theoretical curiosity in the 1980s to a tool for building real systems today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2018: Distributed Learning without Distress</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</guid>
      <description>Bargav Jayaraman presented our work on privacy-preserving machine learning at the 32nd Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2018) in Montreal.
Distributed learning (sometimes known as federated learning) allows a group of independent data owners to collaboratively learn a model over their data sets without exposing their private data. Our approach combines differential privacy with secure multi-party computation to both protect the data during training and produce a model that provides privacy against inference attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>