<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intrinsic Robustness on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/intrinsic-robustness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intrinsic Robustness on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/intrinsic-robustness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ICLR 2022: Understanding Intrinsic Robustness Using Label Uncertainty</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2022-understanding-intrinsic-robustness-using-label-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-2022-understanding-intrinsic-robustness-using-label-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>(Blog post written by Xiao Zhang)&#xA;Motivated by the empirical hardness of developing robust classifiers against adversarial perturbations, researchers began asking the question “Does there even exist a robust classifier?”. This is formulated as the intrinsic robustness problem (Mahloujifar et al., 2019), where the goal is to characterize the maximum adversarial robustness possible for a given robust classification problem. Building upon the connection between adversarial robustness and classifier’s error region, it has been shown that if we restrict the search to the set of imperfect classifiers, the intrinsic robustness problem can be reduced to the concentration of measure problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Estimation of Concentration (ICLR 2021)</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/improved-estimation-of-concentration-iclr-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/improved-estimation-of-concentration-iclr-2021/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on Improved Estimation of Concentration Under ℓp-Norm Distance Metrics Using Half Spaces (Jack Prescott, Xiao Zhang, and David Evans) will be presented at ICLR 2021.&#xA;Abstract: Concentration of measure has been argued to be the fundamental cause of adversarial vulnerability. Mahloujifar et al. (2019) presented an empirical way to measure the concentration of a data distribution using samples, and employed it to find lower bounds on intrinsic robustness for several benchmark datasets.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
