<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Katherine Knipmeyer on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/katherine-knipmeyer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Katherine Knipmeyer on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/katherine-knipmeyer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Research Summit: Surprising (and unsurprising) Inference Risks in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-research-summit-surprising-and-unsurprising-inference-risks-in-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/microsoft-research-summit-surprising-and-unsurprising-inference-risks-in-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the Practical and Theoretical Privacy of Machine Learning Training Pipelines Workshop at the Microsoft Research Summit (21 October 2021):
Surprising (and Unsurprising) Inference Risks in Machine Learning [PDF] The work by Bargav Jayaraman (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) that I talked about on improving membership inference attacks is described in more details here:
Bargav Jayaraman, Lingxiao Wang, Katherine Knipmeyer, Quanquan Gu, David Evans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UVA News Article</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/uva-news-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/uva-news-article/</guid>
      <description>UVA News has an article by Audra Book on our research on security and privacy of machine learning (with some very nice quotes from several students in the group, and me saying something positive about the NSA!): Computer science professor David Evans and his team conduct experiments to understand security and privacy risks associated with machine learning, 8 September 2021.
David Evans, professor of computer science in the University of Virginia School of Engineering and Applied Science, is leading research to understand how machine learning models can be compromised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICLR DPML 2021: Inference Risks for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-dpml-2021-inference-risks-for-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/iclr-dpml-2021-inference-risks-for-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I gave an invited talk at the Distributed and Private Machine Learning (DPML) workshop at ICLR 2021 on Inference Risks for Machine Learning.
The talk mostly covers work by Bargav Jayaraman on evaluating privacy in machine learning and connecting attribute inference and imputation, and recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codaspy 2021 Keynote: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the 11th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy:
When Models Learn Too Much [PDF] The talk includes Bargav Jayaraman&amp;rsquo;s work (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) on evaluating privacy in machine learning, as well as more recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference attacks, and Bargav on attribute inference and imputation:
Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice “When models learn too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/merlin-morgan-and-the-importance-of-thresholds-and-priors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/merlin-morgan-and-the-importance-of-thresholds-and-priors/</guid>
      <description>Post by Katherine Knipmeyer
Machine learning poses a substantial risk that adversaries will be able to discover information that the model does not intend to reveal. One set of methods by which consumers can learn this sensitive information, known broadly as membership inference attacks, predicts whether or not a query record belongs to the training set. A basic membership inference attack involves an attacker with a given record and black-box access to a model who tries to determine whether said record was a member of the model’s training set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
