<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Katherine Knipmeyer on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/katherine-knipmeyer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Katherine Knipmeyer on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/katherine-knipmeyer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Codaspy 2021 Keynote: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/codaspy-2021-keynote-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for my talk at the 11th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy:
 When Models Learn Too Much [PDF]   The talk includes Bargav Jayaraman&amp;rsquo;s work (with Katherine Knipmeyer, Lingxiao Wang, and Quanquan Gu) on evaluating privacy in machine learning (as well as more recent work by Anshuman Suri on property inference attacks, and Bargav on attribute inference and imputation):
 Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice   “When models learn too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merlin, Morgan, and the Importance of Thresholds and Priors</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/merlin-morgan-and-the-importance-of-thresholds-and-priors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/merlin-morgan-and-the-importance-of-thresholds-and-priors/</guid>
      <description>Post by Katherine Knipmeyer
Machine learning poses a substantial risk that adversaries will be able to discover information that the model does not intend to reveal. One set of methods by which consumers can learn this sensitive information, known broadly as membership inference attacks, predicts whether or not a query record belongs to the training set. A basic membership inference attack involves an attacker with a given record and black-box access to a model who tries to determine whether said record was a member of the model’s training set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>