<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>videos on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/videos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in videos on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CrySP Talk: When Models Learn Too Much</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/crysp-talk-when-models-learn-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/crysp-talk-when-models-learn-too-much/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk on When Models Learn Too Much at the University of Waterloo (virtually) in the CrySP Speaker Series on Privacy (29 March 2021):&#xA;Abstract Statistical machine learning uses training data to produce models that capture patterns in that data. When models are trained on private data, such as medical records or personal emails, there is a risk that those models not only learn the hoped-for patterns, but will also learn and expose sensitive information about their training data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DLS Keynote: Is &#39;adversarial examples&#39; an Adversarial Example?</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/dls-keynote-is-adversarial-examples-an-adversarial-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/dls-keynote-is-adversarial-examples-an-adversarial-example/</guid>
      <description>I gave a keynote talk at the 1st Deep Learning and Security Workshop (co-located with the 39th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy). San Francisco, California. 24 May 2018&#xA;Abstract&#xA;Over the past few years, there has been an explosion of research in security of machine learning and on adversarial examples in particular. Although this is in many ways a new and immature research area, the general problem of adversarial examples has been a core problem in information security for thousands of years.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
