<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefferson&#39;s Wheel</title>
    <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/tags/secure-computation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefferson&#39;s Wheel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="//jeffersonswheel.org/tags/secure-computation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jeffersonswheel.org/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//securecomputation.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/pragmaticmpc.jpg&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation&lt;/em&gt;,
co-authored with Vladimir Kolesnikov and Mike Rosulek, is now
published by Now Publishers in their
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nowpublishers.com/SEC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundations and Trends in Privacy and Security&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the book for free (we retain the copyright and are
allowed to post an open version) from
&lt;a href=&#34;//securecomputation.org&#34;&gt;securecomputation.org&lt;/a&gt;, or buy an PDF
version from the published for $260 (there is also a printed $99
version).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;
Secure multi-party computation (MPC) has evolved from a theoretical
curiosity in the 1980s to a tool for building real systems today. Over
the past decade, MPC has been one of the most active research areas in
both theoretical and applied cryptography. This book introduces
several important MPC protocols, and surveys methods for improving the
efficiency of privacy-preserving applications built using MPC. Besides
giving a broad overview of the field and the insights of the main
constructions, we overview the most currently active areas of MPC
research and aim to give readers insights into what problems are
practically solvable using MPC today and how different threat models
and assumptions impact the practicality of different approaches.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2018: Distributed Learning without Distress</title>
      <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jeffersonswheel.org/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Bargav Jayaraman presented our work on privacy-preserving machine learning at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nips.cc/Conferences/2018/&#34;&gt;32&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (NeurIPS 2018) in Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distributed learning&lt;/em&gt; (sometimes known as &lt;em&gt;federated learning&lt;/em&gt;)
allows a group of independent data owners to collaboratively learn a
model over their data sets without exposing their private data.  Our
approach combines &lt;em&gt;differential privacy&lt;/em&gt; with secure &lt;em&gt;multi-party
computation&lt;/em&gt; to both protect the data during training and produce a
model that provides privacy against inference attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34;
    src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rwyWiDyVmjE&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media;
    gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explore two popular methods of differential privacy, output
perturbation and gradient perturbation, and advance the
state-of-the-art for both methods in the distributed learning
setting. In our output perturbation method, the parties combine local
models within a secure computation and then add therequired
differential privacy noise before revealing the model. In our gradient
perturbation method, the data owners collaboratively train a global
model via aniterative learning algorithm. At each iteration, the
parties aggregate their local gradients within a secure computation,
adding sufficient noise to ensure privacy before the gradient updates
are revealed. For both methods, we show that the noise can be reduced
in the multi-party setting by adding the noise inside the
securecomputation after aggregation, asymptotically improving upon the
best previous results. Experiments on real world data sets demonstrate
that our methods providesubstantial utility gains for typical privacy
requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bargavj/distributedMachineLearning&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bargavj/distributedMachineLearning&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bargavj/distributedMachineLearning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bargav Jayaraman, Lingxiao Wang, David Evans and Quanquan Gu. &lt;a href=&#34;//www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/pubs/neurips2018/neurips2018.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distributed Learning without Distress:
Privacy-Preserving Empirical Risk Minimization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nips.cc/Conferences/2018/&#34;&gt;32&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems&lt;/a&gt; (NeurIPS). Montreal, Canada. December 2018. (&lt;a href=&#34;//www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/pubs/neurips2018/neurips2018.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, 19 pages, including supplemental materials)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>