<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Havron on Security Research Group</title>
    <link>//uvasrg.github.io/tags/sam-havron/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sam Havron on Security Research Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Privacy and Security Research at the University of Virginia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//uvasrg.github.io/tags/sam-havron/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>USENIX Security Symposium 2019</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-symposium-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/usenix-security-symposium-2019/</guid>
      <description>Bargav Jayaraman presented our paper on Evaluating Differentially Private Machine Learning in Practice at the 28th USENIX Security Symposium in Santa Clara, California.
Summary by Lea Kissner:
Hey it&amp;#39;s the results! pic.twitter.com/ru1FbkESho
&amp;mdash; Lea Kissner (@LeaKissner) August 17, 2019 Also, great to see several UVA folks at the conference including:
Sam Havron (BSCS 2017, now a PhD student at Cornell) presented a paper on the work he and his colleagues have done on computer security for victims of intimate partner violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plan to Eradicate Stalkerware</title>
      <link>//uvasrg.github.io/a-plan-to-eradicate-stalkerware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//uvasrg.github.io/a-plan-to-eradicate-stalkerware/</guid>
      <description>Sam Havron (BSCS 2017) is quoted in an article in Wired on eradicating stalkerware:
The full extent of that stalkerware crackdown will only prove out with time and testing, says Sam Havron, a Cornell researcher who worked on last year&amp;rsquo;s spyware study. Much more work remains. He notes that domestic abuse victims can also be tracked with dual-use apps often overlooked by antivirus firms, like antitheft software Cerberus. Even innocent tools like Apple&amp;rsquo;s Find My Friends and Google Maps&amp;rsquo; location-sharing features can be abused if they don&amp;rsquo;t better communicate to users that they may have been secretly configured to share their location.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
