<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefferson&#39;s Wheel</title>
    <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/categories/publications/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefferson&#39;s Wheel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="//jeffersonswheel.org/categories/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>When Relaxations Go Bad: &#34;Differentially-Private&#34; Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/when-relaxations-go-bad-differentially-private-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jeffersonswheel.org/when-relaxations-go-bad-differentially-private-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have posted a paper by Bargav Jayaraman and myself on &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1902.08874&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;When Relaxations Go Bad: &amp;ldquo;Differentially-Private&amp;rdquo; Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (code available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bargavj/EvaluatingDPML&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bargavj/EvaluatingDPML&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Differential privacy is becoming a standard notion for performing
privacy-preserving machine learning over sensitive data. It provides
formal guarantees, in terms of the privacy budget, &amp;epsilon;, on how
much information about individual training records is leaked by the
model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the privacy budget is directly correlated to the privacy
leakage, the calibration of the privacy budget is not well
understood. As a result, many existing works on privacy-preserving
machine learning select large values of ϵ in order to get acceptable
utility of the model, with little understanding of the concrete impact
of such choices on meaningful privacy. Moreover, in scenarios where
iterative learning procedures are used which require privacy
guarantees for each iteration, relaxed definitions of differential
privacy are often used which further tradeoff privacy for better
utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we evaluate the impacts of these choices on privacy in
experiments with logistic regression and neural network models. We
quantify the privacy leakage in terms of advantage of the adversary
performing inference attacks and by analyzing the number of members at
risk for exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;myrow&#34;&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;mycolumn&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/cifar_nn_grad_add.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/cifar_nn_grad_acc.png&#34; width=&#34;92%&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Accuracy Loss as Privacy Decreases&lt;br&gt;
(CIFAR-100, neural network model)
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;mycolumn&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/Cifar_nn_grad_mem.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/Cifar_nn_grad_mem.png&#34; width=&#34;98%&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Privacy Leakage&lt;br&gt;
(Yeom et al.&amp;rsquo;s Membership Inference Attack)
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main findings are that current mechanisms for differential privacy
for machine learning rarely offer acceptable utility-privacy
tradeoffs: settings that provide limited accuracy loss provide little
effective privacy, and settings that provide strong privacy result in
useless models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bargav Jayaraman talked about this work at the &lt;em&gt;DC-Area Anonymity, Privacy, and Security Seminar&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://dcaps.info/2019-2-25.html&#34;&gt;https://dcaps.info/2019-2-25.html&lt;/a&gt;) (25 February 2019) at the University of Maryland:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;294ac688ec6d415a9bef17a91e031459&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.77777777777778&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1902.08874&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;When Relaxations Go Bad: &amp;ldquo;Differentially-Private&amp;rdquo; Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bargavj/EvaluatingDPML&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bargavj/EvaluatingDPML&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICLR 2019: Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples</title>
      <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/iclr-2019-cost-sensitive-robustness-against-adversarial-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jeffersonswheel.org/iclr-2019-cost-sensitive-robustness-against-adversarial-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xiao Zhang and my paper on &lt;a href=&#34;https://openreview.net/forum?id=BygANhA9tQ&amp;amp;noteId=BJe7cKRWeN&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost-Sensitive Robustness against Adversarial Examples&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has been accepted to ICLR 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several recent works have developed methods for training classifiers
that are certifiably robust against norm-bounded adversarial
perturbations. However, these methods assume that all the adversarial
transformations provide equal value for adversaries, which is seldom
the case in real-world applications. We advocate for cost-sensitive
robustness as the criteria for measuring the classifier&amp;rsquo;s performance
for specific tasks. We encode the potential harm of different
adversarial transformations in a cost matrix, and propose a general
objective function to adapt the robust training method of Wong &amp;amp;
Kolter (2018) to optimize for cost-sensitive robustness. Our
experiments on simple MNIST and CIFAR10 models and a variety of cost
matrices show that the proposed approach can produce models with
substantially reduced cost-sensitive robust error, while maintaining
classification accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/protecteven.png&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
This shows the results of cost-sensitive robustness training to protect the odd classes. By incorporating a cost matrix in the loss function for robustness training, we can produce a model where selected transitions are more robust to adversarial transformation.
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xiao will present the paper at ICLR in New Orleans in May 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jeffersonswheel.org/a-pragmatic-introduction-to-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//securecomputation.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jeffersonswheel.org/images/pragmaticmpc.jpg&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Pragmatic Introduction to Secure Multi-Party Computation&lt;/em&gt;,
co-authored with Vladimir Kolesnikov and Mike Rosulek, is now
published by Now Publishers in their
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nowpublishers.com/SEC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundations and Trends in Privacy and Security&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the book for free (we retain the copyright and are
allowed to post an open version) from
&lt;a href=&#34;//securecomputation.org&#34;&gt;securecomputation.org&lt;/a&gt;, or buy an PDF
version from the published for $260 (there is also a printed $99
version).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;
Secure multi-party computation (MPC) has evolved from a theoretical
curiosity in the 1980s to a tool for building real systems today. Over
the past decade, MPC has been one of the most active research areas in
both theoretical and applied cryptography. This book introduces
several important MPC protocols, and surveys methods for improving the
efficiency of privacy-preserving applications built using MPC. Besides
giving a broad overview of the field and the insights of the main
constructions, we overview the most currently active areas of MPC
research and aim to give readers insights into what problems are
practically solvable using MPC today and how different threat models
and assumptions impact the practicality of different approaches.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2018: Distributed Learning without Distress</title>
      <link>//jeffersonswheel.org/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jeffersonswheel.org/neurips-2018-distributed-learning-without-distress/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Bargav Jayaraman presented our work on privacy-preserving machine learning at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nips.cc/Conferences/2018/&#34;&gt;32&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (NeurIPS 2018) in Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distributed learning&lt;/em&gt; (sometimes known as &lt;em&gt;federated learning&lt;/em&gt;)
allows a group of independent data owners to collaboratively learn a
model over their data sets without exposing their private data.  Our
approach combines &lt;em&gt;differential privacy&lt;/em&gt; with secure &lt;em&gt;multi-party
computation&lt;/em&gt; to both protect the data during training and produce a
model that provides privacy against inference attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34;
    src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rwyWiDyVmjE&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media;
    gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explore two popular methods of differential privacy, output
perturbation and gradient perturbation, and advance the
state-of-the-art for both methods in the distributed learning
setting. In our output perturbation method, the parties combine local
models within a secure computation and then add therequired
differential privacy noise before revealing the model. In our gradient
perturbation method, the data owners collaboratively train a global
model via aniterative learning algorithm. At each iteration, the
parties aggregate their local gradients within a secure computation,
adding sufficient noise to ensure privacy before the gradient updates
are revealed. For both methods, we show that the noise can be reduced
in the multi-party setting by adding the noise inside the
securecomputation after aggregation, asymptotically improving upon the
best previous results. Experiments on real world data sets demonstrate
that our methods providesubstantial utility gains for typical privacy
requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bargavj/distributedMachineLearning&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bargavj/distributedMachineLearning&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bargavj/distributedMachineLearning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bargav Jayaraman, Lingxiao Wang, David Evans and Quanquan Gu. &lt;a href=&#34;//www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/pubs/neurips2018/neurips2018.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distributed Learning without Distress:
Privacy-Preserving Empirical Risk Minimization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nips.cc/Conferences/2018/&#34;&gt;32&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems&lt;/a&gt; (NeurIPS). Montreal, Canada. December 2018. (&lt;a href=&#34;//www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/pubs/neurips2018/neurips2018.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, 19 pages, including supplemental materials)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>